<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on K.Q. Dreger</title>
    <link>https://dreger.me/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on K.Q. Dreger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dreger.me/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Masthead</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/masthead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/masthead/</guid>
      <description>Hi. I&amp;rsquo;m K.Q. Dreger. These pages are run out of my own pocket and in my spare time. What it lacks in regularity is hopefully made up for in quality.
The sparse design is intentional. I&amp;rsquo;m prone to tinker with the layout, grids, colors, typography. But by keeping things simple, I&amp;rsquo;m more likely to actually write.
(Also, “Kyle” is fine—I just sign my name KQ. My favorite authors all went by first-initial-middle-initial-last-name, and I really like that style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/projects/</guid>
      <description>Edit for iOS Edit is a tasteful place to write. Think of it as a single page of paper, not a notebook. You get a single note, and whatever you leave in the app will be there when you get back. Once you’re done writing, you can send or save your text to anywhere in iOS via the Share Sheet.
Style Guide Audacious Fox follows the New York Times Manual of Style in most cases, and our own in-house version in all others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms &amp; Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Short and sweet:
 You use this website and everything hosted here at your own risk. Anything you download to your computer is also done so at your own risk. All linked to websites are thoroughly vetted; however, if you visit anything not hosted at audaciousfox.net, the liability changes to adhere to those listed in the privacy policy and terms of that website.  Ads I do not run any third-party advertisements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>