<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Kyle Dreger</title>
<link href="http://kyledreger.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
<link href="http://kyledreger.com/"/>
<updated>2012-07-26T11:03:21-04:00</updated>
<id>http://kyledreger.com/</id>
<author>
    <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
    <email>hi@kyledreger.com</email>
</author>


    <entry>
        <title>Oreo</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/oreo.html"/>
        <updated>2012-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/oreo</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend and I talk frequently about spiritual things. We talk about the Bible. We talk about Jesus and His life. Mostly, however, we talk about using God to strengthen our relationship, and help each other grow. We&amp;#8217;re not perfect by any means, but I&amp;#8217;m really blessed to have someone as God-centered as she is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While talking a couple weeks ago, we found ourselves on the topic of us and our relationship with Him. A couple of days focused on each other, and not enough on our spiritual health, left us feeling like we weren&amp;#8217;t clicking as usual. It was here that I stumbled onto a delicious little analogy that summarizes the sort of relationship we&amp;#8217;re striving for. Milk&amp;#8217;s favorite cookie, the Oreo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analogy goes like this: imagine my girlfriend and I as the cookie parts of an Oreo, and God, Jesus and the Holy Spirit as the creamy, delicious filling. If it were just us two cookies, there wouldn&amp;#8217;t be anything to hold us together; we would easily fall apart. However, when you put creamy-center God into the equation, the cookies stick together quite well. Only by holding on for dear cookie life to God can we stay connected, forever, with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This analogy really works for us. Probably because we&amp;#8217;re half crazy, but also because there&amp;#8217;s some real truth in there. Whenever we feel a little off, or just need some encouragement, one of us will text the other &amp;#8220;Oreo,&amp;#8221; and it helps us refocus on what really makes &amp;#8220;us&amp;#8221; work. Loving Jesus truly makes you a better lover, and I&amp;#8217;m sure if He could have tried one, our Lord probably would have loved Oreos too.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Written in the Star(s)bucks</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/written-in-the-starbucks.html"/>
        <updated>2012-06-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/written-in-the-starbucks</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven’t accomplished much writing today. So, in lieu of staying inside and eating more cereal, I put on jeans and and a belt and drove over to my local Starbucks. In a lot of ways, this coffee shop mirrors my writing. There’s not much else I could do here, except write. I can’t load up the Xbox, make something to eat, or try and socialize with the roommates down the hall; just write. It suits me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is why I find myself solo tonight in the local Starbucks. I got here and checked-in with Foursqure, something else I’ve really come to appreciate as time has gone on. Being able to look back at my history of check-ins and see where I’ve gone has been insightful to my life in general. Dustin Curtis once quipped that Foursquare is the Facebook of the future. I don’t know if that is completely true, but the abstracted version of what he’s saying is that the future of social lies in what we’re really doing. Not just status updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny place, Starbucks. I remember when they only use to have coffee and a small array of items. Now they have walls of cups, blends and a full on snack bar. That blueberry coffee cake looks good, but it’s a little too expensive for me right now – I haven’t even finished my grande mocha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with coffee, Starbucks has gotten increasingly good at another thing: seating people really close to one another. This is remarkable on two levels. 1.) People don’t seem to notice that the threshold for what could be considered my “bubble” is dangerously near to being crossed, and 2.) people think you can’t hear them talk at low levels from four feet away. Remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure I look like such a tool right now. Rocking my Apple Macbook with iPhone set beside me as I drink a grande white-chocolate mocha. Thankfully I have no hair, otherwise I’m sure it would complete the look. Out hipstering the hipsters, maybe I have accomplished something tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My coffee has finally reached the point of equilibrium: I can now drink a steady stream and not viciously raze the small village of my tastebuds with scalding lava. Words are fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The barista is pulling out the items from the snack bar now, wrapping them in saran and putting them away for tomorrow. I always knew this sort of thing happened, obviously they can’t leave the food in there indefinitely, but I’ve never actually seen it being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My coffee cup is now empty, after I shotgunned the last teaspoon of pure sugary chocolate confection. Decaf probably would have been a better choice for this time at night, but you don’t go to Starbucks to get decaf. That would be like going to McDonalds to get a salad – a complete waste of time. If you’ve already made it into the building, you are bound by society law to getting that Big Mac with fries, er.. mocha with whipped cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has proven productive. Forcing myself to go somewhere where I’d be cornered, literally and metaphorically, into writing has been successful. This was fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just need to change up the setting and remove the “crutches” preventing you from doing what you love. Kick those crutches out from under you, and you just might stand. Try it, I’ll take you out for coffee afterwards and we can read the awesome thing you wrote. It doesn’t even matter if it sucks, just so long as you did something to give yourself the opportunity to write again. At the end of the night, that’s what will make all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Write it down</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/write-it-down.html"/>
        <updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/write-it-down</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last night, my roommates and I watched Christopher Nolan’s 2000 film, &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0209144/'&gt;Memento&lt;/a&gt;. If you think that Inception, or Pulp Fiction was confusing the first time through, Memento can definitely be added to the list of movies that will give you brain whiplash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without going into the actual story, Memento follows Lenard, a man who cannot create new memories. He remembers everything in his past, just cannot create new memories. “Everything just fades” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only being able to remember what has happened within the last couple minutes, Lenard carries around a Polaroid camera and takes pictures of the key people / places he has been. On the back of the photos, he writes down short notes – clues – to help him piece everything back together when his memories fade again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching this all transpire, the slogan of my favorite paper- notebook maker, Field Notes, came into my mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not writing it down to remember it later. I’m writing it down to remember it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lenard was able to survive purely on the fact that he wrote down the things he knew he would forget. It was a matter of life and death for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of us, however, it’s not a matter of life or death, but rather whether we remember to return the Redbox on time, pick up the milk, or make that phone call. None of these things are huge, but each are important in their own way, and it is a hassle whenever we forget to do them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been scribbling notes down for a couple years now, and I’m still refining my methods. However, one technique which is incredibly effective, and not necessarily apparent, is to write down everything. You really have to push the boundaries of what you’re used to constituting as a “note.” If you started writing down all the little things that clutter up your mind throughout the day (quotes, thoughts for a project, the first lyric of a song), imagine how much less preoccupied your thoughts would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it. Write down everything that makes you think, “hey, I want to come back to this later.” You will feel less cluttered and able to focus better on the task at hand; all while knowing that the awesome thing you thought of will still be there, and awesome, later.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Orientation, questions and the CEO</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/orientation-questions-and-the-ceo.html"/>
        <updated>2012-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/orientation-questions-and-the-ceo</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today marks the end of Orientation Day at &lt;a href='http://timken.com'&gt;The Timken Company&lt;/a&gt;. Hats off to the University relations team for putting together a great program for us; I&amp;#8217;ve been to much shorter programs which felt twice as long. Informative, fun and a great way to get our feet wet the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took plenty of things away from today, including one of the amazing spare lunches (boxed &lt;a href='http://www.honeybakedham.com/catering.asp'&gt;Honey Baked Ham sandwiches&lt;/a&gt;), but what I&amp;#8217;m most impressed with is how well they treat their interns. It&amp;#8217;s a foundation of respect that you feel, even though you&amp;#8217;re the lowest ones on the totem pole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned out to be quite a successful at all the activities we had participated in today, netting three different gift cards as prizes, but something I wasn&amp;#8217;t expecting was a live presentation from the CEO and current President: &lt;a href='http://www.timken.com/en-us/about/leadership/Pages/JamesWGriffith.aspx'&gt;James W. Griffith&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know how many CEO&amp;#8217;s of companies as large as Timken make time to come to an intern orientation day, but there can&amp;#8217;t be many. Seeing President Griffith and being able to spend 45 some minutes listening to him speak and then having our own personal Q&amp;amp;A session was awesome. As much as I respected his position before this morning, I respect him that much more for making time for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='smart_people_ask_questions'&gt;Smart people ask questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that the session with President Griffith reminded me of was an article by Tommy MacWilliam called &lt;a href='http://blog.tommymacwilliam.com/post/17500383225/what-ive-learned-about-smart-people'&gt;What I&amp;#8217;ve Learned About Smart People&lt;/a&gt;. MacWilliam is a student at Harvard and has had the chance to be around &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of incredibly intelligent individuals. From this, and the fact he seems to be a pretty bright guy himself, he&amp;#8217;s noticed that &lt;strong&gt;smart people ask questions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart people are different. If they don’t understand something, or even if they think they understand something, they’ll ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was this idea that persuaded me to raise my hand and ask President Griffith a question. I don&amp;#8217;t remember exactly what I asked, it was something about how heavily Timken takes a business&amp;#8217;s patents into account when looking to acquire that company, but I knew I had to ask something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s not to say I wasn&amp;#8217;t really nervous and scribbled down a draft of my question to get the wording right, but after asking, not only did I feel proud - I also got a great response and direct conversation with the CEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking questions, especially when you are surrounded by people way smarter than yourself is always going to be intimidating. You don&amp;#8217;t want to sound stupid, or ask something that isn&amp;#8217;t relevant, but regardless how nervous you feel, just ask. Make it a good question and ask. It&amp;#8217;s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='alarm_set_for_710_am'&gt;Alarm set for 7:10 AM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow will mark my first &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; day of work for The Timken Company. It seems like a decade has passed since I first submitted my application and resumé. I&amp;#8217;m ready to dive in. Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Lens</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/lens.html"/>
        <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/lens</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just made my first camera lens in Adobe Illustrator. Following the awesome &lt;a href='http://vector.tutsplus.com/tutorials/illustration/create-an-aperture-style-camera-lens-icon/'&gt;tutorial on Tuts+&lt;/a&gt;, it took me about two hours to complete. I&amp;#8217;ve got lots of improving to do, but I&amp;#8217;ve always wanted to learn how to make something this intricate and downright cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration is a world I&amp;#8217;ve long looked at, but never really set foot in like I did with web design. However, after only two hours working on the camera lens, I realized that I have a strong passion for this type of design. Being able to create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; I can think of makes me feel enlivened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With enough effort, anyone can learn practically anything with the Internet. Hopefully by the end of this summer, I will be a much better illustrator than I am now, and have learned a new way to create things I enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Typekit</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/typekit.html"/>
        <updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/typekit</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been using &lt;a href='http://typekit.com'&gt;Typekit&lt;/a&gt; to serve up the fonts you see here on &lt;a href='http://kyledreger.com'&gt;kyledreger.com&lt;/a&gt; and have been very pleased. Normally, when you want to use a custom font on your website, you need to make sure it&amp;#8217;s a font that your visitors have installed on their machines. If they don&amp;#8217;t have that particular font, their browser will revert to using a default, and ugly, backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Typekit lets you use any font you want, even if the visitor doesn&amp;#8217;t have it installed. They currently offer serveral different pricing plans: Free, Personal, Portfolio, Performance and Business. Difference between the plans includes how many fonts you can access, and how many websites you can use them on. For now, the Free plan works great for me, but if I ever have a client that needed custom fonts, I know where I&amp;#8217;m going to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I love Helvetica and Georgia, I can&amp;#8217;t get enough of the PT Sans that I&amp;#8217;m currently using. After actual page content, good typography might be the most important thing you can add to your site.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Thank you</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/twenty.html"/>
        <updated>2012-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/twenty</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I turn twenty. It&amp;#8217;s almost unbelievable that our bodies, for how fragile they are, can even &lt;em&gt;hold up&lt;/em&gt; for that long. Nevertheless, two decades in these shoes and I thank Him for every minute in them. There are other people that deserve some thanks as well and today feels like great opportunity do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='to_those_older_than_me'&gt;To those older than me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for knowingly, or unknowingly, helping to guide me as I&amp;#8217;ve grown. As the oldest of my siblings, I&amp;#8217;m accustomed to being the first one to try something new. Though I would be nervous going down an untraveled road, I took peace in knowing that I had people around me who had done it before. Thank you for never giving me an excuse to quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, thank you for all the work you&amp;#8217;ve done, and will do in your lives. All my accomplishments have been built upon the work someone else has done. As Isaac Newton said, &amp;#8220;If I have seen further, it is by standing on the shoulders of giants.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='to_those_younger_than_me'&gt;To those younger than me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your spirit and reminding me that life is all perspective. I&amp;#8217;m at an age where I acknowledge how short life really is - it boggles my mind that in just ten years I will be thirty with a completely different life than now. However, no matter how old I get, whenever I see you all working hard and enjoying life, it motivates me to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='to_those_i_call_my_peers'&gt;To those I call my peers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for being there to experience and share in the adventure. Having people in your life who are experiencing the same things at the same time as you is awesome. It is this shared experience that is the glue of our generation. As a new generation grows up, let us not forget the days of video cassettes, dial-up Internet, or phones with antennas. These memories are dear to me, as I&amp;#8217;m sure they are to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='to_my_family_and_girlfriend'&gt;To my family and girlfriend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear family: I love you guys. Brother, sisters, parents, cousins, grandparents, aunts, uncles, my dogs - unfaltering in support and providing nothing but love towards me even in failure. You guys are the most unique, crazy group of people I&amp;#8217;ve ever met and I&amp;#8217;m proud to call you all my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear girlfriend: I could not have asked Him for a more wonderful individual to share my life with. Seriously, you&amp;#8217;re my best friend and you make me very, very happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='to_my_god'&gt;To my God&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for blessing me with the life I have and the people in it. Although I sometimes feel guilty for being so blessed when some have so little, let me only work harder to use my gifts in ways that will help others. Thank you for each day I get to wake up and experience your grace. Help me to be an even better echo of your message these next twenty years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='to_you'&gt;To you&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading. It may be my birthday, but I hope you have, or make, an awesome day for you too.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>One year</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/one-year.html"/>
        <updated>2012-03-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/one-year</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been one year since I started dating my girlfriend. She is my best friend, someone I confide in all the time and my spiritual support. I&amp;#8217;ll never forget the day she invited me to coffee, our first date, and how I made sure to ask her back &amp;#8220;same time, same place&amp;#8221; the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not have asked God for a better partner and I thank Him for her every day. I ask that He look over us as we embark on another year together and that we remember that nothing is too big for Him to handle. I cannot wait to keep growing with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love you, sweetheart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='my best friend' src='http://dl.dropbox.com/u/418570/kyledreger/one-year.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Cold Writing</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/cold-writing.html"/>
        <updated>2012-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/cold-writing</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve found that as I write papers for class, sometimes I hit a wall. This isn&amp;#8217;t a full case of writers block, rather I feel the enthusiasm start to fade. What was just a feverish output of thoughts to typed characters is starting to die. Eventually, I&amp;#8217;ve stopped writing and am looking at my cursor blink. Blink. Blink. Blink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when I hit Command + &amp;#8220;N&amp;#8221; and open up a new document. Without thinking more than a few seconds, I start &amp;#8220;cold&amp;#8221; writing about anything I want. Stacking wood, running in the snow, listening to instrumental music - anything that comes to mind. The block is gone, my writing flame has recaptured it&amp;#8217;s intensity and I&amp;#8217;m having fun. I&amp;#8217;ll pound out 500 words on this new topic in the time it took me to get 200 for the first one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m done, I return to my original document. Every single time I do, the writers block is gone and I get back to typing. This sort of &amp;#8220;cold writing&amp;#8221; to jumpstart my spirit is a great exercise. I don&amp;#8217;t do it every time I write a paper, however once or twice throughout the course of a longer essay is normal. I&amp;#8217;m not worried about the time I lose when doing these short side-articles; the small amount of time I invest to reset my thoughts and come back focused is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my ideas for blog posts have come from cold writing. In fact, this post you&amp;#8217;re reading was being written as I worked on a paper assigned for when I get back from spring break. Writing to get rid of writer&amp;#8217;s block, go figure.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Writing Like A Hacker</title>
        <link href="http://kyledreger.com/writing-like-a-hacker.html"/>
        <updated>2012-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
        <id>http://kyledreger.com/writing-like-a-hacker</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract: From history to English, I write all my school papers like a hacker. Using text editors without support for spell checking or formatting, I create a frictionless creative flow which allows me get my ideas out faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been writing for a long time, even though I&amp;#8217;m not the best at it. Nevertheless, ever since I was a little kid, I would sit down and write stories and journal away my life. Today, however, instead of crayons and pens on paper, I type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When most people I see sit down to write, they fire up Microsoft Word and begin typing. However, they rarely get more than a few lines before they stop. They move the cursor back a couple steps and then right-click on a bright, red underlined misspelled word. After clicking the correctly spelled version, they continue on, only to stop a couple of lines later. Without even have a paragraph&amp;#8217;s worth of content and they are editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This completely kills the creative flow a writing process allows them to enter. Stopping every couple lines to fix something that has no impact on what they meant only wastes their time. It also can violently kick them out of a creative state of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not their fault, it&amp;#8217;s the tool they are using. Microsoft Word is a word processor, meaning that it&amp;#8217;s job is to alert you to every misspelling, grammatical error and let you format your final document. This is all great for when you need to format your document, but when you&amp;#8217;re starting out with ideas, it can crush them because you get caught up in all those other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='hackers_do_it_differently'&gt;Hackers do it differently&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer &amp;#8220;hackers&amp;#8221; aren&amp;#8217;t all malicious individuals trying to grab your VISA digits off the local Starbucks wifi. Most of them are just like me: enthusiastic about computers and the tools we use to interact with them. Most of our tools are simple. They do one or two things, but they do them phenomenally well. While the toolsets can vary greatly between individuals, the one tool every hacker has is a text editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of text editors is that they are practically ubiquitous with computers themselves. Pre-installed on almost every operating system, a text editor&amp;#8217;s default file format is the .txt (text) file extension, one of the most compatible format in the world. Working with text files, I&amp;#8217;ve never run into the problem of &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; being able to open my documents on a computer other than my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A text editor is exactly what it sounds like and rarely anything more. It &lt;strong&gt;edits&lt;/strong&gt; text and lets you do it quickly. The list of what it doesn&amp;#8217;t do is strict:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No spell checking&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No bulleted lists&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No images&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No links&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No bolding&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No italics&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No underlining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just text. The reason hackers love this is that it removes distraction. When I&amp;#8217;m sitting down to write code, I want to focus on code. The color and font are irrelevant. This makes writing code incredibly straightforward - just write code. Why can&amp;#8217;t english writers have the same benefit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='my_writing_process'&gt;My writing process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking this bare-bones approach to writing code, I decided that I wanted to apply the same principle to English writing. Almost 90% of my time spent writing looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open up &lt;a href='http://iawriter.com'&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt; - a super-simple text editor. One font, one size, no options.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Start dumping my thoughts into the page. My goal isn&amp;#8217;t to have a nicely formatted paper, it&amp;#8217;s to get all my ideas out and into words. My application doesn&amp;#8217;t point out misspellings, so often I don&amp;#8217;t even notice any of them until much later when I review.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Once I&amp;#8217;ve gotten all my ideas out, and expanded the new ones that came while I was writing, I do basic editing. Paragraph breaks, content flow and overall structure.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I read the entire document a couple times, refining it each time and adding, or moving, thoughts and sentences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m done, the paper is almost done. I haven&amp;#8217;t wasted a second being pulled backwards into my text to fix glowing red errors, or changing the font. For the entirety of my time, I&amp;#8217;ve been writing. Once I&amp;#8217;m done, I copy and paste the text into something like Microsoft Word to do the final touchup and spell checking. I print out the final product and I&amp;#8217;m done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing in a bare-bones text editor is like writing on pen and paper again. When I was little and, in my opinion, at my most creative, little red lines didn&amp;#8217;t show up under misspellings in my journal. I was free to write and get out my ideas. Bringing the new digital medium back to that level allows a writer to do what they&amp;#8217;ve been trying to do: write.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <!-- <author>
        <name>Kyle Dreger</name>
            <uri>http://kyledreger.com/about.html</uri>
        </author> -->
    </entry>

</feed>