<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>_posts_archives on K.Q. Dreger</title>
    <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in _posts_archives on K.Q. Dreger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 15:16:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Yet</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-26-not-yet.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 15:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-26-not-yet.html</guid>
      <description>Ben Brooks and Michael Rockwell both brought up the topic of going iOS only, and the maintenance that goes into tuning and running macOS (née OS X). Brooks:
 I lost 30 minutes to just managing my Mac that morning.
  Yet my iPad was just there, did it’s job and stayed the hell out of my way, and never once demanded I do housekeeping on it. The apps update in the background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapchat and Sharing First Drafts</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2016-05-23-sharing-on-snapchat.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 12:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2016-05-23-sharing-on-snapchat.html</guid>
      <description>Recently, Chris Bowler asked the following question in his The Weekly Review email:
 So what does Snapchat offer people other than another distraction from getting work done? That’s a serious question. Do you have an answer? Let me know, I’d love to better understand how and why people use it.
 By &amp;ldquo;people,&amp;rdquo; Mr. Bowler is referring to other creatives, those who might work in design, art, or writing fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-05-01-speech-writing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 18:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-05-01-speech-writing.html</guid>
      <description>I never actually &amp;ldquo;finish&amp;rdquo; a speech, I just run out of time before I have to give it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Typography.</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-04-14-mb.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 12:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-04-14-mb.html</guid>
      <description>Thoroughly enjoying all the little details on Practical Typography by Matthew Butterick. Writer, ty­pog­ra­pher, law­yer. This guy does it all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-04-13-design.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 12:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-04-13-design.html</guid>
      <description>RSS subscribers: As more publications move to Medium, better get used to truncated feeds for your…
Continue reading on Medium »</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-04-13-west-wing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 17:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-04-13-west-wing.html</guid>
      <description>The West Wing Weekly is one of those shows that I could see kicking off a whole slew of TV series-turned-podcasts with members of the cast as guests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Press Photo of the Year</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-21-world-press-photo-of-the-year.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 13:24:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-21-world-press-photo-of-the-year.html</guid>
      <description>Out of 82,951 photos, from 5,775 photographers, an image from Australian photographer Warren Richardson has been selected as World Press Photo of the Year. His photo, taken at the Hungarian-Serbian border, depicts a man helping pass a baby underneath the border&amp;rsquo;s razor wire fence. Such a haunting image. Be sure to check out the gallery of other winners, and scroll down beneath each photo to see the GPS, camera, and technical details of the shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeing Springboard</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-02-02-freeing-springboard.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-02-02-freeing-springboard.html</guid>
      <description>Would this work?

It&amp;rsquo;s a simple change, but the perceived value is immediate. You can put icons anywhere on the existing grid, eliminating the need to implement hackery just to make apps easier to launch. In fact, the current (forced) top-to-bottom, left-to-right layout of the iOS Springboard is one of the reasons I find less appeal in the larger iPhone 6 and iPhone 6 Plus screens.
I know Reachability sort of helps, but forcing users to make three taps to open an app (two for Reachability and one for the app itself) is less than ideal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My next Three Books</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-01-29-three-books.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-01-29-three-books.html</guid>
      <description>I recently had the opportunity to pick up three books that I had been meaning to buy. I&amp;rsquo;ve rented and borrowed copies of these titles before, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy to finally own them for myself:
The New York Times Manual of Style — If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do serious blogging, you should be keeping a personal style guide. Style guides are incredibly useful because they help keep your writing consistent. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you like the serial comma or if you spell website as two words, just make your editorial decisions consistent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wabi-sabi</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2015-01-25-wabi-sabi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2015-01-25-wabi-sabi.html</guid>
      <description>Through an odd series of events, which I will expand on another time, I went from owning an iPhone 5s to an iPhone 6 to my current iPhone 5.
Before this rapid iPhone transition, I had stayed on the near-cutting edge of iPhone releases. I liked owning the newest thing out of Cupertino, and every time I got the upgrade, I would tell myself that this was the last one I needed for the next five years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Budgeting</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-12-12-budgeting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-12-12-budgeting.html</guid>
      <description>At its core, budgeting is setting aside money from each paycheck to go towards a specific goal or category of expenses. That&amp;rsquo;s it. You get paid, you give those dollars a job, and then you only spend whatever you have saved for a particular category. To give you an idea of what this looks like, here are some of the categories that my wife and I have set up for our budget:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typed for Mac</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-12-02-typed-for-mac.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-12-02-typed-for-mac.html</guid>
      <description>OS X does not need another Markdown text editor.
In fact, Macs already ship with the purest Markdown experience available: TextEdit in plain text mode. However, there are a number of alternatives that can make writing Markdown more convenient: iA Writer (and Pro), Byword, WriteRoom, Markdown Pro, Ulysses, LightPaper, and Mou to name a few.
Today, add Realmac Software’s Typed to the list.
There isn’t a lot to distinguish Typed from the other minimalistic Markdown editors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Audacious</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-20-something-audacious.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 18:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-20-something-audacious.html</guid>
      <description>For a while now, I have wanted to stop writing at kyledreger.com.
I love writing, and I think it helps me work through my own thoughts. However, I have always wanted to write in a place that didn&amp;rsquo;t scream &amp;ldquo;me.&amp;rdquo; I wanted a place where I could grow the brand beyond myself.
Some thoughts:
This is the web column I want to read. It will feature articles and musings at the intersection of art and technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commencement</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-05-10-commencement-speech.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-05-10-commencement-speech.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Lifelong Learners,&amp;rdquo; delivered by Kyle Quinn Dreger on May 10, 2014, at the University of Mount Union. Video recording is also available.
Welcome Hello everyone, and thank you for coming today. Before we begin, I want to thank Dr. and Mrs. Giese, members of the Board of Trustees, and all those individuals who work day-in and day-out at Mount Union, who have helped us get here today.
And I would be remiss if I didn&amp;rsquo;t thank Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Gruber Reviews the iPhone 5C and 5S</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-18-gruber-iphone-5c-5s.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-18-gruber-iphone-5c-5s.html</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re going to read just one review of the new iPhones, Gruber&amp;rsquo;s is the one to check out. It&amp;rsquo;s thorough and hits on the key features most users, not just us nerds, care about. He also makes a heartening comment about the iPhone 5C&amp;rsquo;s plastic build:
 It feels slick but not slippery. Feel-wise it’s not too dissimilar from the old 3G and 3GS (both of which I still have sitting here in my office), but it presents a far more premium overall effect than those previous forays into plastic iPhones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSA: iOS 7 Ships Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-17-ios-7-ships-tomorrow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-17-ios-7-ships-tomorrow.html</guid>
      <description>Just a reminder to all my friends and readers that iOS 7 is rolling out tomorrow for all devices. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what time it will be available, pushing out any software to nearly 700,000,000 devices is no small task - be patient.
In terms of what to expect, iOS 7 is a large departure from what we&amp;rsquo;re familiar with. However, the new design and underlying philosophy are still founded on consistency and reliability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Places for Desktop Wallpapers</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-15-great-desktop-wallpaper-sources.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-15-great-desktop-wallpaper-sources.html</guid>
      <description>I keep my Mac&amp;rsquo;s desktop immaculately clean. No icons, hide the Dock, and only the essentials in the Menu Bar. This serves two purposes:
 My desktop is always available as a &amp;ldquo;holding place&amp;rdquo; for files I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on. I get the full screen to display a beautiful desktop wallpaper.  The first one is a personal preference of mine, but the second is something I think everyone enjoys. Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve whittled down my wallpaper sources to just two places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five C</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-13-iphone-five-c.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-13-iphone-five-c.html</guid>
      <description>Some thoughts on the new iPhone 5C, and why it&amp;rsquo;s going to be the most popular version Apple&amp;rsquo;s ever sold.
One of my favorite iPhones to hold was the iPhone 3GS. In my opinion, it was one of the best-feeling phones Apple ever made. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I don&amp;rsquo;t appreciate the luxurious feel ushered in with the iPhone 4, I do. But the 3GS felt like, on an ideological level, the everyman&amp;rsquo;s phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-10-the-best.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-10-the-best.html</guid>
      <description>After writing about [the gear I use]({% post_url 2013-09-09-my-gear %}), some people asked me how I actually decide what &amp;ldquo;the best&amp;rdquo; stuff is.
In reality, most of what I consider &amp;ldquo;the best&amp;rdquo; is subjective (not everyone likes iOS, but it&amp;rsquo;s worked great for me). However, I do have a philosophy about what makes truly great stuff, and it&amp;rsquo;s derived from a quote by Shawn Blanc - pulled from an article he wrote while searching for a new camera:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Gear</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-09-my-gear.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-09-my-gear.html</guid>
      <description>Note: Due to moving hosts, my relative image links are breaking. I&amp;rsquo;m working on it.

I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to write a &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rsquo;s my gear&amp;rdquo; piece. I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated seeing what other people are using, and I personally have a deep love for the gear I use.

A 13-inch, mid 2013 Macbook Air is my only machine. This is the third Apple laptop that I&amp;rsquo;ve owned, however it is the first that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever purchased directly from Cupertino.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curse of Unlimited Data</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-04-unlimited-data-and-upgrading-my-phone.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-04-unlimited-data-and-upgrading-my-phone.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m one of the few lucky Verizon customers who still has an unlimited data plan. However, as I begin to look at possible upgrades for my three-year-old iPhone 4, I find myself in the predicament of getting an upgrade without being forced into a capped data plan.
Unfortunately, people in my situation only have two real options:
 Buy an unsubsidized, relatively-new device, off eBay or Craigslist and activate my number on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jumping in</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-02-jumping-in.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-02-jumping-in.html</guid>
      <description>As part of my senior project, I have the unique opportunity to spend the next semester writing for this website. That&amp;rsquo;s correct, I get to work on my own little web column for school credit - how awesome is that?
Stemming from a deep admiration for the Shawn Blanc&amp;rsquo;s of the world - those who jump in, feet first, to writing full-time for their websites - I&amp;rsquo;m excited to be doing just that for the next fifteen weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Arc Touch mouse</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-08-01-arc-touch-mouse-review.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-08-01-arc-touch-mouse-review.html</guid>
      <description>The time had finally come for my trusty Microsoft Wireless 3500 to die. For the past two years it had served me well, but the middle button - which had been inconsistent these past few months - finally failed. Given I had only spent $19 on it at a Target Back-to-School sale, I felt it was an opportune time to upgrade.
Off the glowing recommendation of a friend at work, I decided to pick up a Microsoft Arc Touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief review of Vesper</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-07-13-vesper.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-07-13-vesper.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve tried tens of iOS note-taking applications over the years. Among others, I&amp;rsquo;ve tested Simplenote, Elements, iA Writer, and Notesy, but none were able to evoke the feelings I get when writing something into my Field Notes notebook. I was looking for delight.
Then I found Vesper.
Vesper is a different kind of note-taking application under the mantra &amp;ldquo;Collect your thoughts,&amp;rdquo; and developed by three gentlemen all seasoned in apps and design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What matters</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-07-10-what-matters.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-07-10-what-matters.html</guid>
      <description>Family, friends, and the people around you matter. Helping these people matters too. One of the ways I try to help people is through creating software.
But software is only useful if it helps fix a real problem. As a programmer, it is my implicit job to find problems and break down ways to solve them. Here is where many, myself included, get lost.
I get caught up thinking the problem to be solved is a global one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social scoreboards</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-06-20-social-scoreboards.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-06-20-social-scoreboards.html</guid>
      <description>I went on a small rant about social scoreboards the other day and have been thinking about social analytics ever since.
Remember that competition to reach a million followers between Ashton Kutcher and CNN? We&amp;rsquo;re mildly obsessed with stats related to us, and sites like Twitter and Facebook make sure to put those numbers where we can see them. Social analytics can be a powerful tool when used as data, but I worry when those numbers start causing change in emotions and actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>URLs for Email</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-02-06-erondu-urls-for-email.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-02-06-erondu-urls-for-email.html</guid>
      <description>This morning I read an interesting article by Jared Erondu titled If Emails Worked Like URLs. His idea revolves around the notion of prematurely assigning subfolders to an email message based on the addressed it was sent to. In his example, sending an email to john@johndoe.com/hire would automatically sort the email into a folder/label named &amp;ldquo;hire.&amp;rdquo;
As he noted in his post, Gmail already lets you do something like this. For instance, messages sent to johndoe@gmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am a remix</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-01-10-i-am-a-remix.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-01-10-i-am-a-remix.html</guid>
      <description>99% of what you create in life is a remix of someone else&amp;rsquo;s work. Enjoy the fact you didn&amp;rsquo;t have to start from scratch. Isacc Newton put it succinctly, &amp;ldquo;If I have seen further, it is by standing on the shoulders of giants.&amp;rdquo;
The design I&amp;rsquo;ve created here is a remix - one based on a decade&amp;rsquo;s worth of inspiration from all corners of the web. Hat tips to Signal vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix your Mount Union .EDU email</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-01-03-fix-your-mount-union-email.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-01-03-fix-your-mount-union-email.html</guid>
      <description>UPDATE #3: This whole post is pretty much irrelevant now. Besides the slightly vitriolic nature, the entire Outlook Web App was recently updated to match the aesthetics / functionally of Outlook.com and is incredibly more usable. Post will remain here for posterity.
UPDATE #2: I&amp;rsquo;ve found the magical URL which only makes you sign in once: outlook.com/owa/mountunion.edu. Just bookmark that and you&amp;rsquo;ll be good to go.
UPDATE: I simplified the instructions for those looking to set up your mobile email without the required passcode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tinkerer</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-11-13-the-tinkerer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-11-13-the-tinkerer.html</guid>
      <description>I want to tell you about the Tinkerer.
The Tinkerer was a good web designer, a good programmer and a good writer. But having things come easy to him eventually led to trouble.
Creative was his mind, that he started dozens of small projects - though few ever saw completion. Hours were spent tweaking the colors, and fonts on his website. At first, this could be seen as an admirable dedication to the details, but in reality it was a vacuum for the any spare time he had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trash</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-08-11-trash.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-08-11-trash.html</guid>
      <description>My mom gave me eyes, a nose and terrible knees. If my genetic history is to be taken seriously, around 40 years old I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to hit the streets for a run anymore. And that sucks.
Because I love running on pavement. The subtle, muted drum of my Nike shoes on the ground warrants days I run without an iPod. I love the quiet, exercise and time to think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oreo</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-07-17-oreo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-07-17-oreo.html</guid>
      <description>My girlfriend and I talk frequently about spiritual things. We talk about the Bible. We talk about Jesus and His life. Mostly, however, we talk about using God to strengthen our relationship, and help each other grow. We&amp;rsquo;re not perfect by any means, but I&amp;rsquo;m really blessed to have someone as God-centered as she is.
While talking a couple weeks ago, we found ourselves on the topic of us and our relationship with Him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GORUCK GR1 Delivered</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-19-gr1-delivered.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-19-gr1-delivered.html</guid>
      <description>My GORUCK GR1 arrived today.
I want to write a longer review after I get done dragging it through Georgia next week, but here are some quick impressions:
 Damn this is a nice bag. I&amp;rsquo;m 5&amp;rsquo;8″, weigh around 150 and this bag fits great. My previous Radio Ruck was a good fit, but the GR1 really hugs my body with all my gear in it. The GR1 can fit a ton, the pockets are deep and the slightly angled bottom keeps the weight higher on my back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market share</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-06-18-market-share.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-06-18-market-share.html</guid>
      <description>I was speaking with my father this morning around 2:00 AM and somehow we got on the topic of WWDC.
My father is not as savvy as I when it comes to computer technology, however he holds his own amongst his peers. As I was explaining Apple&amp;rsquo;s newest flagship laptop, the Macbook Pro Retina, I could see him grimacing as I explained the lack of upgrade options and removal of an optical drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Left out</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-14-left-out.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-14-left-out.html</guid>
      <description>After a few more days with the iOS 6 beta, it&amp;rsquo;s still going pretty well. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve had more time to experiment with it, I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to notice the bugs that are still there. Nothing groundbreaking, but more than I had first, hopefully, assumed there were.
In my earlier post on iOS 6, I said:
 iOS 6 doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anything I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, Passbook and Maps aren&amp;rsquo;t active yet, that makes me go “WOW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New cleats</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-12-new-cleats.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-12-new-cleats.html</guid>
      <description>Short one today. I got my new soccer cleats today - Adidas Predator Absolions. I use to wear Predators all the time when I was younger, but once I got into my sophomore year of high school, I switched to Pumas. Ever since then, I had bought the same pair of Puma shoes off eBay, or wherever I could find them; they were the perfect size and fit. However, after all these years, it&amp;rsquo;s finally time to return and give adidas another go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WWDC 2012</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-06-11-wwdc-2012.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-06-11-wwdc-2012.html</guid>
      <description>WWDC. I wait all year for this. It&amp;rsquo;s on my bucket list of events I want to attend. As someone joked on Twitter, it&amp;rsquo;s the event where Apple-lovers find out what they&amp;rsquo;re getting for Christmas. This also might have been the most important WWDC since Steve Jobs announced the original iPhone. New hardware, new software and an amazing completely redesigned Macbook Pro easily filled the two hours on stage - Jony Ive could wax romantic about the new Macbook Pro to me all day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starbucks</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-06-08-written-in-the-starbucks.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-06-08-written-in-the-starbucks.html</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t accomplished much writing today. So, in lieu of staying inside and eating more cereal, I put on jeans and and a belt and drove over to my local Starbucks. In a lot of ways, this coffee shop mirrors my writing. There&amp;rsquo;s not much else I could do here, except write. I can&amp;rsquo;t load up the Xbox, make something to eat, or try and socialize with the roommates down the hall; just write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build stuff, tell people</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-07-build-stuff-tell-people.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-07-build-stuff-tell-people.html</guid>
      <description>Build stuff and tell people. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple mantra. Anyone who makes something (code, designs, gear) should be doing this. You&amp;rsquo;re only going to get better at what you do.
Take the company GitHub for example. They&amp;rsquo;re building awesome stuff that lets users share and publish their code, and then writing awesome blog posts about how they did it. Their latest blog post, Designing GitHub for Windows talks about the recently released Windows counterpart to their GitHub for Mac app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashpoint</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-05-flashpoint.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-05-flashpoint.html</guid>
      <description>I loved 24. I nearly shed tears during the finale when Chloe had to shut off the drone camera on Jack. It was the first TV series I actually watched each week, as it aired. Now, was it, at times, a little out there? Sure. Did Jack Bauer have a complex that always required people to put their weapons on the ground? Absolutely. Did CTU always choose to ignore the fact that the mole was 95% likely to be one of their own agents?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, Nintendo and a TV</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-04-apple-nintendo-and-tv.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-04-apple-nintendo-and-tv.html</guid>
      <description>I want to talk about the Apple TV. The one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist yet.
In episode 3 of The Talk Show with John Gruber and John Moltz, the duo talked briefly talked about the Apple TV. The WWDC schedule has been released, and there are an unusually large amount of sessions listed as &amp;ldquo;TBA&amp;rdquo; - usually the sign that the content of those sessions will relate to something announced in kickoff keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To the point</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-02-to-the-point.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-02-to-the-point.html</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow will be my first experience on a roller coaster.
Now sure, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the better part of my childhood riding fair “rides,” but none of the holy-cow-we&amp;rsquo;re-upside-down variety.
For my inaugural experience, I will be going to Cedar Point in Sandusky, Ohio. Living not too far from Cedar Point my whole life, I never really recognized what a unique place it is. Opened in 1870, it is the second oldest operating amusement park in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great games - Kingdom Rush</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-01-kingdom-rush.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-06-01-kingdom-rush.html</guid>
      <description>Upon returning to the apartment this evening, my roommates and I began talking about some of our favorite online games. Back when I was just starting high school and before HTML5 came along, Flash games were me and my friends past time. We spent hours, literally hours, playing some of the classics like Bloons, Mini Putt, and more. My personal favorite, however, were the tower defense games. From the Wikipedia page for Tower defense:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iA Writer 1.2.2</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-30-ia-writer-122.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-30-ia-writer-122.html</guid>
      <description>Typically, I forget about the Mac App Store. I don&amp;rsquo;t have it in my dock and I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the need to buy an app for my Mac in a while. However, occasionally I&amp;rsquo;ll remember and open it up to check for updates. Boy was there a present waiting for me today.
iA Writer, which is hands-down my favorite writing app on any platform, was updated to version 1.2.2 this week with one very important new feature: copy as HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write it down</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-05-29-write-it-down.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-05-29-write-it-down.html</guid>
      <description>Last night, my roommates and I watched Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s 2000 film, Memento. If you think that Inception, or Pulp Fiction was confusing the first time through, Memento can definitely be added to the list of movies that will give you brain whiplash.
Without going into the actual story, Memento follows Lenard, a man who cannot create new memories. He remembers everything in his past, just cannot create new memories. “Everything just fades” he says.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing with paper</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-26-drawing-with-paper.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-26-drawing-with-paper.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this iPad for a couple weeks now, and something that always seems to surprise me is how easy it is for people to just pick up and start using.
This is particularly highlighted by my recent attempts to put Xubuntu on my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s aging iBook. Device drivers be darned.
When people pick up the iPad, there is some level of intuitiveness that they just get. Most recently, I was letting my girlfriend explore around and she opened up Paper by 53.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart people ask questions</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-05-14-orientation-questions-and-the-ceo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-05-14-orientation-questions-and-the-ceo.html</guid>
      <description>Today marks the end of Orientation Day at The Timken Company. Hats off to the University relations team for putting together a great program for us; I&amp;rsquo;ve been to much shorter programs which felt twice as long. Informative, fun and a great way to get our feet wet the first day.
I took plenty of things away from today, including one of the amazing spare lunches (boxed Honey Baked Ham sandwiches), but what I&amp;rsquo;m most impressed with is how well they treat their interns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lens</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-10-lens.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-10-lens.html</guid>
      <description>I just made my first camera lens in Adobe Illustrator. Following the awesome tutorial on Tuts+, it took me about two hours to complete. I&amp;rsquo;ve got lots of improving to do, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to learn how to make something this intricate and downright cool.
Illustration is a world I&amp;rsquo;ve long looked at, but never really set foot in like I did with web design. However, after only two hours working on the camera lens, I realized that I have a strong passion for this type of design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-04-21-twenty.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-04-21-twenty.html</guid>
      <description>Today, I turn twenty. It&amp;rsquo;s almost unbelievable that our bodies, for how fragile they are, can even hold up for that long. Nevertheless, two decades in these shoes and I thank Him for every minute in them. There are other people that deserve some thanks as well and today feels like great opportunity do so.
To those older than me: Thank you for knowingly, or unknowingly, helping to guide me as I&amp;rsquo;ve grown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 things I&#39;ve learned in 19 years</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-05-04-nineteen.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-05-04-nineteen.html</guid>
      <description>This past April, I turned 19. Almost two decades worth of time have been given to me and I wanted to take a little time to reflect on five core things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned these past 228 months. I write this for my siblings; that they can use it as a roadmap around the pits I fell in.
One: Don&amp;rsquo;t be cool — I&amp;rsquo;ve spent so much of my life trying to be cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When bloggers die</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-01-20-when-bloggers-die.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-01-20-when-bloggers-die.html</guid>
      <description>The question &amp;ldquo;what happens when bloggers die?&amp;quot; has been bugging me a lot lately. It seems that in a day in age where content creation is so immediate, so instantaneous, the last thing anyone seems to be thinking about is when all that creation eventually stops. Now, this isn&amp;rsquo;t suppose to be cynical, or depressing, simply inquisitive. What is going to happen if, when, bloggers start to die, taking their archives of content with them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;So is San Francisco really the perfect system font for Apple’s products? It’s complicated.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-07-martiancraft-san-francisco.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-07-martiancraft-san-francisco.html</guid>
      <description>MartianCraft&amp;rsquo;s Nick Keppol wrote two incredibly detailed posts on the typographic strengths and weaknesses of Apple&amp;rsquo;s new sans-serif typeface. Part one looks at San Francisco in contrast with Lucida Grande, Helvetica Neue, and DIN. Part two focuses on San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s various weights, with particular interest paid to the nuances between San Francisco UI, Text, and Compact.
I have a non-Retina Macbook Pro, and the general legibility of OS X was dramatically increased after I upgraded to El Capitan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Design is about solving problems that humans have, not problems that products have&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-25-baker-design.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-25-baker-design.html</guid>
      <description>Mills Baker:
 And if our best designers, ensconced in their labs with world-class teams, cannot reliably produce successful products, we should admit to ourselves that perhaps so-called “design science” remains much less developed than computer science, and that we’d do well to stay humble despite our rising stature. Design’s new prominence means that design’s failures have ever-greater visibility. Having the integrity and introspective accuracy to distinguish what one likes from what is good, useful, meaningful is vital; we do not work for ourselves but for our users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Dumb&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-20-blanc-dumb.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-20-blanc-dumb.html</guid>
      <description>Shawn Blanc, on the recent news regarding smartwatches:
 So often I&amp;rsquo;d be standing in line at the grocery store and I&amp;rsquo;d pull out my iPhone to see what time it was. Then, out of sheer habit, I&amp;rsquo;d swipe to unlock and the next thing you know I&amp;rsquo;m mindlessly scrolling through tweets or reading emails without actually acting on them. Then the line would move, I&amp;rsquo;d put the iPhone back in my pocket, and if you&amp;rsquo;d asked me what time it was I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even tell you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;For Immediate Release&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-18-hoefler-and-co.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-18-hoefler-and-co.html</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Hoefler &amp;amp; Co. issued a public statement in regards to Tobias Frere-Jones suing Jonathan Hoefler. The company&amp;rsquo;s General Counsel, Michael Burke:
 Last week, designer Tobias Frere-Jones, a longtime employee of The Hoefler Type Foundry, Inc. (d/b/a &amp;ldquo;Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones&amp;rdquo;), decided to leave the company. With Tobias&amp;rsquo;s departure, the company founded by Jonathan Hoefler in 1989 will become known as Hoefler &amp;amp; Co. &amp;hellip;
  It goes without saying that all of us are disappointed by Tobias&amp;rsquo;s actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;iMessage Purgatory&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-13-imessage.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-13-imessage.html</guid>
      <description>Adam Pash:
 I recently switched from an iPhone to Android, and discovered shortly thereafter that my phone number was still associated with iMessage, meaning that any time someone with an iPhone tried texting me, I’d receive nothing, and they’d get a “Delivered” receipt in their Messages app as though everything were working as expected.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Special&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-30-df-special.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-30-df-special.html</guid>
      <description>Out of all the nostalgic posts regarding the Macintosh&amp;rsquo;s 30th birthday, I like John Gruber&amp;rsquo;s anecdotal piece the best:
 For one thing, they [the original Macintosh team] sweated the details. The greatest testimony to their genius is just how much of that original design is recognizable in today’s Mac OS X 10.9. A Mac user from 1984 could sit down in front of an iMac or MacBook today and recognize it as a successor to that original machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Summing up years of work in one sentence&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-05-lol-my-thesis.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-05-lol-my-thesis.html</guid>
      <description>Incredibly funny, one-sentence summaries of academic research papers. A great way to kick off the new semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 words on design</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-09-30-design100.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-09-30-design100.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m stealing this &amp;ldquo;100 words&amp;rdquo; exercise from Jeremy Keith. It&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic idea, and as Mr. Keith says, &amp;ldquo;when it comes to writing, there are no shortcuts.&amp;rdquo;
I also believe that writing can be a great way to learn. Take any topic, write 10,000 words about it, and I bet you&amp;rsquo;ll finish smarter than you started.
For this experiment, I want to spend some time exploring what it takes to design great digital products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1Password 4 for Android Arriving June 10</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-24-1password-android.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-24-1password-android.html</guid>
      <description>Good news for Android users. David Chartier:
 All new features will be unlocked and free for everyone to use through August 1, 2014. After that, 1Password 4 for Android will go into a reader mode, and all features can be unlocked for an in-app purchase.
 No coincidence that this free trial period overlaps with the Google I/O conference on June 25-26. That&amp;rsquo;s the perfect time to have a new, well-respected Android app available and free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1Password 4.5 Released for iOS</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-24-1password-4-5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-24-1password-4-5.html</guid>
      <description>Quite easily the best $18 (currently on sale for $9) you can spend on the App Store, and it&amp;rsquo;s one of my must-have apps.
If you are interested in seeing what password management is all about, Robert McGinley Myers, writing for The Sweet Setup, has a great review of 1Password and explanation of why this sort of app is important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 Million iPhones Sold, 200 Million Users on iOS 7</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-23-nine-million-iphones-200-million-on-ios-7.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-23-nine-million-iphones-200-million-on-ios-7.html</guid>
      <description>Apple just announced that they sold over nine million new iPhones this past weekend, breaking all previous records for a product launch. They also noted that over 200 million users have upgraded to iOS 7.
iPhone Sales Make no mistake, nine million is a huge number for Apple on a product launch weekend. However, since we weren&amp;rsquo;t given the breakdown of sales between the 5C and 5S, I&amp;rsquo;m going to take this one with a grain of salt — especially since Apple sold over five million iPhone 5s on launch weekend last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&lt;em&gt;Sherlock&lt;/em&gt; Mini-Episode</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-27-sherlock-mini-episode.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-27-sherlock-mini-episode.html</guid>
      <description>Until Sherlock&amp;rsquo;s return on January 19, this seven-minute mini-episode will have to suffice. I&amp;rsquo;m so excited for this show to come back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A $19 Billion Partnership</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-18-whatsapp-partnership.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-18-whatsapp-partnership.html</guid>
      <description>Interesting choice of words from WhatsApp founder Jan Koum on the company&amp;rsquo;s blog:
 If partnering with Facebook meant that we had to change our values, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have done it. Instead, we are forming a partnership that would allow us to continue operating independently and autonomously. Our fundamental values and beliefs will not change. Our principles will not change. Everything that has made WhatsApp the leader in personal messaging will still be in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Break for Exams</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-06-exams.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-06-exams.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently within 10 days of finishing the Fall Semester, and that means my exams are right around the corner. Given the amount of time and work that is required to study for my tests, KDHQ will be moving to an intermittent publishing schedule until December 16. This is only temporary, and you can expect posting to resume as normal after we get through next week.
If you&amp;rsquo;re currently in school, good luck on any exams or tests you may have coming up, and be sure to check out [some of my tips for keeping productive despite a heavy workload]({% post_url 2011-09-09-search-and-destroy %}).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case for Bordered Buttons in iOS 7</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-27-sinclair-ios-buttons.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-27-sinclair-ios-buttons.html</guid>
      <description>iOS app designer and devloper, Jared Sinclair:
 iOS 7&amp;rsquo;s designers have abandoned bordered buttons in favor of borderless colored text. I think this choice is unjustifiable. It is the root cause of my deep dislike for how it feels to use iOS 7. It introduces unnecessary tension and makes everything less usable than it ought to be.
 Sinclair, who works on the excellent App.net client Riposte, raises some valid points about iOS 7&amp;rsquo;s usability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Change to Linked Items</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-01-meet-excerpts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-01-meet-excerpts.html</guid>
      <description>Over the past two months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been linking to various articles, apps, and items that I&amp;rsquo;ve thought my readers would enjoy. However I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that the amount of commentary I&amp;rsquo;ve been adding to each linked item has been dropping — this is not something I want.
To counter this trend, the linked items will be taking a different form over the coming weeks. Firstly, I&amp;rsquo;ll be renaming the linked items to &amp;ldquo;excerpts&amp;rdquo; — something I&amp;rsquo;ve unashamedly borrowed from Michael Lopp of Rands in Repose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A less Pro Macbook</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-09-04-a-less-pro-macbook.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-09-04-a-less-pro-macbook.html</guid>
      <description>(Update: I ended up sticking with my Macbook Pro. I love it too much.)
I recently got myself a 13&amp;rsquo; Macbook Pro. This thing flies. It is absolutely great for anything that needs a little extra horsepower and it performs really well with anything I throw at it. However, it feels like overkill. More importantly, it is making me feel like I&amp;rsquo;m losing touch with what I really need.
I don&amp;rsquo;t want power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Look at Firefox OS 2.0</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-10-firefox-os2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-10-firefox-os2.html</guid>
      <description>Change the typeface from Fira Sans to Helvetica Neue, and tell me what OS this looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Look at Pixar&#39;s New Short Film &#34;Piper&#34;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-25-pixar-piper.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-25-pixar-piper.html</guid>
      <description>Sabrina Imbler, writing for Audubon:
 To create Piper, Barillaro and his entire team entered the Sanderlings’ world. They spent weekends on beaches all over the Bay Area, meeting at 5 a.m. on a dusty road under a bridge in search of the birds. “Half of us were chasing around different beaches and calling each other on cell phones until we found a flock we could get close to,” Barillaro says.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note on Touch</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-20-touch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-20-touch.html</guid>
      <description>Touch is a fundamental part of how humans build relationships. We hug, we shake hands, we high-five. Touch is one of the most intimate ways to build a relationship that we know. When Apple made interaction with your device exclusive to the touch of fingers, and nailed the user experience, the depth and strength of the relationships we built with those devices was fundamentally changed.
It is because our hands are such an intimate form of communication that I&amp;rsquo;m wary of strapping a smartwatch to my wrist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Small Exchange with Solebon LLC</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-28-solebon-interview.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-28-solebon-interview.html</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago, I noticed that iOS word game Letterpress appeared to have [changed owners from Loren Brichter&amp;rsquo;s Atebits to Solebon LLC][me]. After some time had passed, I reached out to Solebon to get a little more information about the acquisition. We had a short exchange of emails, and that conversation is below.
 Solebon LLC: Solebon acquired Letterpress from Atebits in December 2015. We had approached Loren Brichter in 2Q of 2015 but he wasn&amp;rsquo;t interested in selling at that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Soft Murmur</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-02-a-soft-murmur.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-02-a-soft-murmur.html</guid>
      <description>I write better with background noise, and lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying the ambient noise from A Soft Murmur. This site allows you to generate an array of background sounds by adjusting the volume levels of six different sounds: rain, thunder, fire, waves, birds, and humans.
I have a nice library of instrumental music tracks in iTunes, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to a lot of A Soft Murmur lately. Bonus: it works great on iOS as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Usability Audit on Myself</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-11-19-usability-audit.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-11-19-usability-audit.html</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s nothing quite like tearing apart your own work,1and that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I did after looking at the usability of kyledreger.com.
Most of the changes I made came from the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten from readers and from my own observation of people using the site. Although this design is quite different from the previous version, I feel that I&amp;rsquo;ve addressed a number of usability issues that make the site more enjoyable to visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Year of Nothing New</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-19-durr-a-year-of-nothing-new.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-19-durr-a-year-of-nothing-new.html</guid>
      <description>It seems I wasn’t the only one who wanted to mentally, physically, and spiritually start cleaning out the clutter that seems to accrue with time. Sarah Durr, my good friend and future sister-in-law, writing over on her blog Life, Love and Words, says she’s giving up buying anything new for a whole year. This part is my favorite:
 Then I started asking myself: What is the reason we own anything other than what we need?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABC&#39;s One-On-One with Tim Cook</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-26-abc-and-tim-cook.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-26-abc-and-tim-cook.html</guid>
      <description>ABC News has put up a video of their one-on-one interview with Apple CEO Tim Cook. David Muir, ABC&amp;rsquo;s interviewer, and Cook discussed the new Mac Pro, Apple&amp;rsquo;s increasing focus on manufacturing within the U.S., and the government&amp;rsquo;s transparency. Craig Federighi and Bud Tribble made guest appearances in the video, but they were not taped while speaking.
In regards to the government, Cook was adamant that no “backdoor” exists on Apple&amp;rsquo;s servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIs Are Re-Writing History</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-07-auto-awesome.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-07-auto-awesome.html</guid>
      <description>Rob Smith:
 And I’m sure, at some point in the not to distant future, a jury will be shown a photo that was altered without a single human being involved, without a trace of awareness by the prosecution, defence, judge, accused, or victim. And they’ll all get an impression from that moment that never happened, possibly of a husband’s lack of adequate concern soon after his wife’s mysterious disappearance. It’ll be “Gone Girl” with SkyNet knobs on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alan Rickman dies at 69</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-14-alan-rickman-dies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-14-alan-rickman-dies.html</guid>
      <description>After &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; hit theaters, my imaginary, book-based version of Severus Snape was replaced with Alan Rickman. As I read, and reread, my way through Harry Potter, I remember Snape&amp;rsquo;s dialogue taking on Rickman&amp;rsquo;s permeating, apathetic tone. For me, Rickman made the books better.
Many people will remember Rickman for his role in Die Hard or his stage performances, but I, and I suspect many of my peers, will remember him as one of the &amp;ldquo;best damn antagonists&amp;rdquo; our generation could ask for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Kindle Update</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-04-kindle-update.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-04-kindle-update.html</guid>
      <description>Looks like a solid improvement, particularly when it comes to navigating the UI via touch. However, the increased focus on social media and &amp;ldquo;Sharing Made Easy&amp;rdquo; is concerning. My Kindle is one of few devices where I can consume media without distraction. In this regard, I&amp;rsquo;m OK with new social channels through which to send content, but if the Kindle ever starts receiving notifications, I&amp;rsquo;ll be in a personal hell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon&#39;s 30-Minutes-or-Less Delivery by Drone</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-02-bezos-and-amazons-drones.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-02-bezos-and-amazons-drones.html</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos sat down with Charlie Rose and unveiled Amazon&amp;rsquo;s next big step for their fulfillment centers: delivery by drone in under 30 minutes.
 Jeff Bezos: These generations of vehicles, it could be a 10-mile radius from a fulfillment center. So, in urban areas, you could actually cover very significant portions of the population. And so, it won&amp;rsquo;t work for everything; you know, we&amp;rsquo;re not gonna deliver kayaks or table saws this way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Apple a Day</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-31-apple-meets-with-fda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-31-apple-meets-with-fda.html</guid>
      <description>Last December, Apple executives met with the FDA to discuss mobile medical applications, perhaps indicative of a growing interest surrounding health-focused devices. Nick Bilton for the New York Times Bits Blog:
 Among the participants from Apple were Jeff Williams, senior vice president of operations; Bud Tribble, vice president of software technology at Apple; Michael O’Reilly, who joined Apple last year; and an employee from Apple’s government affairs department.
 Some big names from Apple&amp;rsquo;s side to say the least, which, as Bilton describes, means this was probably not a typical meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An iPad Painting of Morgan Freeman</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-03-lambert-paints-morgan-freeman.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-03-lambert-paints-morgan-freeman.html</guid>
      <description>Kyle Lambert, a talented visual artist, recently completed, what he&amp;rsquo;s calling, &amp;ldquo;The world&amp;rsquo;s most realistic finger-painting&amp;rdquo;:
 I recently discovered that it was possible to create incredibly high resolution (4k) paintings using only my iPad, and I wanted to see just how far I could push digital artwork and paint a true photorealistic portrait. [&amp;hellip;]
  The finished painting is made up of around 285,000 brush strokes and took more than 200 hours to complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry, Sad, Wow, Haha, Like and Love</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-30-facebook.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-30-facebook.html</guid>
      <description>Sarah Frier, reporting for Bloomberg Businessweek, wrote an excellent profile on Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Chief Product Officer Chris Cox and upcoming Facebook Reactions. In addition to profiling Cox, Frier also underscores the whole story with Cox&amp;rsquo;s latest project: Facebook Reactions—an attempt to extend the ubiquitous and iconic blue thumbs-up:
 The like button is the engine of Facebook and its most recognized symbol. A giant version of it adorns the entrance to the company’s campus in Menlo Park, Calif.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animagraffs; Not Your Average Gif</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-06-19-animagraffs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-06-19-animagraffs.html</guid>
      <description>Truly incredible animations of complex mechanisms by Jacob O&amp;rsquo;Neal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Information Privacy</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-22-privacy-and-apple.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-22-privacy-and-apple.html</guid>
      <description>Apple:
 We publish all request data permitted by law, but we believe our customers deserve to know more about what their governments and law enforcement agencies are requesting. We are actively engaged with the White House, as well as policymakers and government regulators around the world, to allow for more accurate and complete disclosures and reforms to overreaching surveillance laws and practices.
 If you use Apple devices, I encourage you to skim through this page; it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to understand how your data is being handled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple OS X Beta Program</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-22-appleseed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-22-appleseed.html</guid>
      <description>Apple:
 The OS X Beta Seed Program gives users the opportunity to run pre-release software. Test-drive beta software and provide quality and usability feedback that will help make OS X even better.
 This is pretty big news. Before today, you had to have an Apple Developer account ($99 a year) to download and install the pre-release betas of OS X on your Macs. Now, anyone can do it for free — just be sure to back-up your system before doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple WWDC Set for June 2</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-03-wwdc-2014.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-03-wwdc-2014.html</guid>
      <description>Exciting news. Returning to the Moscone Center in San Francisco, tickets to the week-long conference cost $1,599 a pop. In the past, attendance has been around 5,000.
One big change from last year: instead of first-come-first-serve, tickets to this year&amp;rsquo;s conference will be offered to registered applicants by random selection. Considering that WWDC 2013 sold out in under 2 minutes, this should help ensure that everyone has a fair chance at attending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple: Thirty Years of Mac</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-24-apple-thirty-years-of-mac.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-24-apple-thirty-years-of-mac.html</guid>
      <description>Featuring a two-minute video, interactive timeline, and high-quality images of (nearly) every Macintosh, Apple&amp;rsquo;s new mini-site pays beautiful respect to the past 30 years of the Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arms Race</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-20-arms-race.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-20-arms-race.html</guid>
      <description>Just last month, at the Mobile World Conference, Samsung revealed the Gear 2 and Gear 2 Neo, two new devices based off their original Gear smartwatch that had launched last summer. Notably, Samsung&amp;rsquo;s latest iterations will no longer use Android as the operating system, instead opting for Tizen; a mobile os that Samsung has much more control over.
Yesterday Google announced Android Wear, an extension to Android that is intended for use in &amp;ldquo;wearables&amp;rdquo; - specifically, smartwatches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assembly language love affair</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-03-01-assembly-love.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-03-01-assembly-love.html</guid>
      <description>I have a love / hate relationship with assembly language.
Things I hate: It&amp;rsquo;s an archaic language. Unless you are working on microchip design, you are probably never going to work with it. Assembly language programmers have to worry and keep track of every single byte of memory - you&amp;rsquo;re minipulating it by hand. Basically, the training wheels of high-level languages like Java and C++ are off and you have to manage everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austin Mann Takes the iPhones 6 to Iceland</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-23-mann-iphone-camera.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-23-mann-iphone-camera.html</guid>
      <description>Say whatever you will about speed, memory, apps, pixel density, weight, thickness, latency, materials, battery, LTE, NFC, Wi-fi, and cloud integration, but if the camera sucks, then — for me — so does the phone.
The iPhones 6 camera does not suck. Fantastic reviewing by Austin Mann.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beats Music</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-13-beats-music.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-13-beats-music.html</guid>
      <description>Beats, the company behind the popular Beats by Dre headphones, is launching a new online music subscription service on January 21. Considering how well-known the company is for their headphones, which have garnered clout as premier hardware, this launch will bring a large dose of publicity to the online music subscription arena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being present for prayer</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-08-05-being-present-for-prayer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-08-05-being-present-for-prayer.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found a really good way to pray.
One of my favorite times to pray is right once I wake up. Unfortunately, I have found it hard to just sit down and start praying after rising from sleep. Often my mind is full of things from the day and the literal noise around me makes it hard to empty my mind and be present for the prayer. I started experimenting a little each morning, trying to find anything I could do to help me clear my thoughts and create an open and quiet time to pray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Excerpts in RSS</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-05-rss-changes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-05-rss-changes.html</guid>
      <description>If you use my RSS feed to subscribe to the site, you should begin to see a small change I implemented this week. Basically, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a small link (this little icon: ✖) to the bottom of all [excerpt posts]({% post_url 2013-12-01-meet-excerpts %}), which points back to the RSS item on kyledreger.com.
Hopefully this helps my readers who follow along exclusively through the RSS feed. Do let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better to Rent or Buy?</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-22-rent-or-buy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-22-rent-or-buy.html</guid>
      <description>Aimed at those who are looking to invest in a house, the New York Times has updated their fantastic &amp;ldquo;Rent or Buy&amp;rdquo; calculator. Not only is the new version more sophisticated (with over 20 different variables you can adjust), but it is also a great example of vector-based, interactive graphing done right on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betteridge&#39;s Law of Headlines</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-05-betteridges-law-of-headlines.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-05-betteridges-law-of-headlines.html</guid>
      <description>Speaking of [dishonest reporting]({% post_url 2013-10-19-foolish-bgr %}), Ian Betteridge has a simple way to quickly filter through most of the sensationalist news out there today:
 Any headline which ends in a question mark can be answered by the word no.
 Through personal experience, this has been proven correct time and time again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Cartel Guides</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-14-big-cartel-guides.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-14-big-cartel-guides.html</guid>
      <description>Big Cartel, the makers of a customizable online store for your creative goods, has a delightful micro-site that features small guides filled with &amp;ldquo;Practical advice for everything you may encounter throughout your life as an artist and entrepreneur.&amp;rdquo;
Each guide is short, informative, and well designed. My favorites were the ones on product photography, copyright, and taxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike ride</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-01-29-bike-ride.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-01-29-bike-ride.html</guid>
      <description>I have to share how amazing the weather is right now. It&amp;rsquo;s 57F on a Tuesday night at 20:54 in the evening. The campus is wet from a slight rain and residual snow, but dry enough for me to ride my bike. The sky is clear, you can see a flawless night sky, and the softest breeze flows around every building. I have a jacket and soccer pants on, but no hat or gloves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief Hands-On with the New iPhones</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-21-brief-thoughts-on-the-iphone-5c-and-5s.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-21-brief-thoughts-on-the-iphone-5c-and-5s.html</guid>
      <description>After hitting golfballs for an hour at the range with my brother, I convinced him to swing by our local Verizon Wireless store to check out the iPhone 5C and 5S. Here are some brief thoughts:
iPhone 5C Walking up to the Apple-dedicated section of the store, the first thing that catches your eye is the color of the 5C demo units. A little thicker than the current iPod Touches, the extra weight makes the plastic body feel very much like a premium device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buckeye Boys State 2014</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-06-19-bbs-2014.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-06-19-bbs-2014.html</guid>
      <description>If it&amp;rsquo;s been quiet around here, it&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;ve been gone for about a 10 days. However, in my rush to leave, I forgot to leave a notice — I apologize.
Every year, I have the opportunity to work with some of the most incredible individuals I know at the American Legion&amp;rsquo;s Buckeye Boys State (BBS) program. As a counselor, I was in charge of 40 high school juniors, 24 hours a day, for eight days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building 3D with Ikea</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-06-ikea.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-06-ikea.html</guid>
      <description>Kirsty Parkin, writing for CGSociety.org:
 Today, around 75% of all IKEA’s product images are CG, and they have a ‘bank’ of about 25,000 models. &amp;ldquo;These are all created at a ridiculously high resolution,&amp;rdquo; explains Martin, &amp;ldquo;We render them in 4Kx4K, and they need to hold up to that resolution. We need to be able to do whatever we like with the renderings - print them on large walls in the stores if we need to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canceling my noise</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-08-02-canceling-my-noise.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-08-02-canceling-my-noise.html</guid>
      <description>My brother got some great noise canceling headphones a while back. I was skeptical at how well they would work, how much can earphones really cancel the noise around you, but once I tried them I was impressed. Sliding them over your ears and flipping a switch, all extra noise around me began to filter out, leaving me in silence.
This got me thinking about how these headphones work. When you switch them on they begin to, in real time, filter out the noise around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate The Mac</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-23-celebrate-the-mac.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-23-celebrate-the-mac.html</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow will mark 30 years since Steve Jobs first unveiled the original Macintosh (video). To help celebrate, Jonathan Zufi, the man behind the ICONIC Book I linked to a while back, has created a website called Celebrate The Mac where he has uploaded high-quality photographs of nearly every Mac from the past 30 years. Personally, my favorites are from his &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; collection.
Compared to some of the competitors of the time, it is not hard to see why the Macintosh&amp;rsquo;s design was considered beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Bowler on Mindfulness and Quality</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-13-bowler-mindful.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-13-bowler-mindful.html</guid>
      <description>Chris Bowler:
 When we buy stuff, the end result is we have to take care of it. Store it. Clean it. Back it up. The more stuff we have, the more work is involved and the more stressed we can become because of it. This fact is magnified when the stuff we buy is junk.
 Exactly. All stuff has a cost, beyond that of its price tag. Invest in quality gear, and it will save you pain in the long run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromebooks Selling Well in Education</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-02-chromebooks-and-edu.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-02-chromebooks-and-edu.html</guid>
      <description>Mark Hearn, writing for 9to5Google:
 During its Atmosphere Live event, Google’s Sundar Pichai announced that the company’s Drive cloud storage platform has over 240 million active users, up 190 from million since June. The Google executive also revealed that Chromebooks are largest selling EDU device in the US approaching a 50 percent share compared to 5 percent 18 months ago.
 I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt that Chromebooks are selling well; they&amp;rsquo;re cheap and meet the web-based needs of most students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clymer on the Apple Watch</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-11-clymer-apple-watch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-11-clymer-apple-watch.html</guid>
      <description>Benjamin Clymer is the founder and editor of Hodinkee, a well-respected voice in the field of wristwatches. I&amp;rsquo;m new to Hodinkee, but it seems I&amp;rsquo;m late to the party. The New York Times called Mr. Clymer &amp;ldquo;the high priest of horology,&amp;rdquo; and after browsing the site, I can see why: his writing style is clearly expressed and enjoyable, and his perspective astute. But enough about my new favorite website.
Mr. Clymer was invited to the Apple Event a few days ago, and he got time in the hands-on area to assess the Apple Watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coca-Cola Presents: The Friendly Twist</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-28-coca-cola-twist.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-28-coca-cola-twist.html</guid>
      <description>Coca-Cola made bottles that require two bottles to open. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big pop drinker, but this video from might be one of the coolest (and quirkiest) things I&amp;rsquo;ve seen from a soft-drink company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffeescript</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-26-coffeescript.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-26-coffeescript.html</guid>
      <description>Today, I learned about CoffeeScript.
CoffeeScript is one part of the three part formula I&amp;rsquo;m looking to learn more about. The other two parts are Ruby on Rails and Spine.js. Part of this inspiration comes from @destroytoday and his venture into this area of web app development. I really admire his work and his tweets on the subject have been really helpful to point me in the right direction.
So CoffeeScript, what is it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold writing</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-03-06-cold-writing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-03-06-cold-writing.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found that as I write papers for class, sometimes I hit a wall. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a full case of writers block, rather I feel the enthusiasm start to fade. What was just a feverish output of thoughts to typed characters is starting to die. Eventually, I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped writing and am looking at my cursor blink. Blink. Blink. Blink.
This is when I hit Command + &amp;ldquo;N&amp;rdquo; and open up a new document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2010-08-27-hello-college.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2010-08-27-hello-college.html</guid>
      <description>Just started college. Unpacked and ready to go. My initial thought?
Wow, there are a lot of girls here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College take two</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-08-19-college-take-two.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-08-19-college-take-two.html</guid>
      <description>Really excited to be moving back to Mount Union. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to get back into the swing of college life and return to soccer with our team.
When I look back at the beginning of my freshman year, I can&amp;rsquo;t believe how much I&amp;rsquo;ve grown since then. I have a million times more confidence, an amazing, supportive girlfriend and my brother will make for an awesome roommate.
I&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot of goals for this year, but I&amp;rsquo;m keeping my mind open to be directed by whatever He calls me to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confessions of an appaholic</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-09-28-appaholic.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-09-28-appaholic.html</guid>
      <description>(Alternative title: Why I deleted my credit card from iTunes)
I&amp;rsquo;ll admit it. I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat of an appaholic. But I&amp;rsquo;m changing that, and conquering my impulse buying at the same time.
iPhone apps appeal to me. They hover nicely in that psychologically-pleasing price range of .99 cents to make each purchase not sting as much as it probably should. New todo list manager? Sure, I&amp;rsquo;ll check it out! What&amp;rsquo;s that, it&amp;rsquo;s like Angry Birds, except with mice and cheese?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Better Passwords</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-16-better-passwords.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-16-better-passwords.html</guid>
      <description>Jesse Gardner has a brilliant way to give each of your sites a unique, yet memorable, password. He does this by starting with a common &amp;ldquo;key&amp;rdquo; phrase or password, and then changing that key, based on the site it is being used for:
 The beauty of this system is that if someone hacks one of your accounts and gets your password, they’ll have a single, unique password that’s not useful anywhere else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative cycle</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-12-12-creative-cycle.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-12-12-creative-cycle.html</guid>
      <description>Admidst my finals, I wanted to take a break and share an excerpt from one of my papers. I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether it&amp;rsquo;s the lack of sleep, or overdose of caffeine, but I&amp;rsquo;m particularly proud of this closing paragraph:
 Ask any creative - writer, designer or artist - and they will tell you that their work is never done. Even in our downtime, our minds are constantly growing organic ideas planted in the soil of our experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cupertino Council Approves Apple&#39;s &#39;Campus 2&#39;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-16-apple-campus-2-approved.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-16-apple-campus-2-approved.html</guid>
      <description>This is going to be one of the most beautiful, architecturally-unique headquarters in the world, and it&amp;rsquo;s now been approved by a unanimous vote from Cupertino&amp;rsquo;s city council.
Whenever I see news about Apple&amp;rsquo;s new campus, I wish Jobs were still here; he would&amp;rsquo;ve loved seeing this project get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Routines of Creative People</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-07-09-creative-routines.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-07-09-creative-routines.html</guid>
      <description>Fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day One for iOS 7</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-13-day-one-ios-7-update.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-13-day-one-ios-7-update.html</guid>
      <description>One of the ways that I chronicle my life is through the action of journaling. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t always have time to sit down and write out long reflections on the day. Back when I was a young boy, I used to carry around little steno notebooks and write about my day as it was happening.
I still carry around little notebooks, but I&amp;rsquo;ve long since moved all my journaling to the digital realm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-clutter Your Social Networks, Part One</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-12-18-declutter.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-12-18-declutter.html</guid>
      <description>Most things in life, left unchecked, tend to fall into chaos. I find this particularly true regarding the number and quality of the updates I receive through social networks. The problem is that we&amp;rsquo;ve become desensitized to the value of our own time, and we continue to add new Facebook friends or follow people on Twitter without closing off some of the existing network.
Imagine a pack permanently strapped to your back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Ms. Tina Brown</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-12-dear-ms-tina-brown.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-12-dear-ms-tina-brown.html</guid>
      <description>I tried to sending the following message through the Tina Brown Media contact form, but the message wouldn&amp;rsquo;t send (I assume it was exceeding the server&amp;rsquo;s maximum number of allowed characters). Nonetheless, the remarks I am addressing took place publicly, so I feel the apology should as well.
 Ms. Brown,
Forgive me for using the contact form intended for Women in the World, but I was unable to find any means of contacting you specifically, other than Twitter, which I avoided because of its informal nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deleting several online accounts</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-03-28-deleting-accounts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-03-28-deleting-accounts.html</guid>
      <description>This evening, I posted a tweet:
 Instagram, Snapchat, Foursquare, IFTTT, and Medium all got the axe this past week.
 Here&amp;rsquo;s the expanded explanation.
Instagram: This was the most difficult account to close. I joined Instagram the moment they opened registration. I remember looking at terribly faux vignette photos from Jack Dorsey, back when he was in the closed beta. I catalogued most of my college life on Instagram with an iPod Touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Describing RSS</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-31-describing-rss.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-31-describing-rss.html</guid>
      <description>Since running this website is part of an academic project, I have been asked, perhaps more often than usual, to describe several of the technologies that I am using. Most non-technical people can generally grasp the idea of a statically-generated site and domains / hosting, but one topic that seems to take an extra round of explaining is RSS.
Thankfully, Brent Simmons has a fantastic way of explaining the protocol, and its purpose, which I will be stealing for the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Principles</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-14-adactio-design.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-14-adactio-design.html</guid>
      <description>Jeremy Keith has collected an impressive list of design manifestos and principles, regarding both digital and anlogue design, from a number of different companies and notable individuals. I like seeing how others prioritize different aspects of design, but the resonating message seems to be this: design for the users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doug Bowman (@stop) to Leave Twitter</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-21-stop-twitter.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-21-stop-twitter.html</guid>
      <description>Doug Bowman, Twitter&amp;rsquo;s Creative Director for the past five years, is leaving the company:
 It’s a cliché in our tech industry that companies and founders start with a vision that includes the grandiose notion of changing the world. What Twitter has enabled, is enabling, and will continue to enable is nothing short of just that. As Biz says, Twitter is not a triumph of technology, it is a triumph of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckDuckGo!</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-01-ddg.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-01-ddg.html</guid>
      <description>DuckDuckGo, the privacy-focused search engine, just announced a new partnership with Yahoo. This partnership isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily new, perhaps more renewed, as DuckDuckGo has utilized Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s BOSS (Build Your Own Search Service) API for years. That said, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what DuckDuckGo was going to do when Yahoo announced it was discontinuing the BOSS API earlier this year.
Now we know.
DuckDuckGo will continue to get results, and a few extra features like date filtering on results, from Yahoo by way of a custom integrations between each service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eight days without Facebook</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-02-10-eight-days-without-facebook.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-02-10-eight-days-without-facebook.html</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been eight days since [I deactivated my Facebook account]({% post_url 2012-02-02-byebye-facebook %}). After being truly logged out for more than a week, here are a few of the interesting things I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed:
Facebook: the 40 minute hour This week without Facebook may have been one of the most productive, non-exam weeks of my life. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I was spending an inordinate amount of time on the site to begin with, but taking away the 10-20 minute visits every couple hours has been great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elie Wiesel Dies at 87</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-02-elie-wiesel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-02-elie-wiesel.html</guid>
      <description>Joseph Berger for the New York Times:
 Elie Wiesel, the Auschwitz survivor who became an eloquent witness for the six million Jews slaughtered in World War II and who, more than anyone else, seared the memory of the Holocaust on the world’s conscience, died on Saturday at his home in Manhattan. [&amp;hellip;]
  “He raised his voice, not just against anti-Semitism, but against hatred, bigotry and intolerance in all its forms,” [President Obama] said Saturday in a statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk on Model S Fire</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-06-musk-model-s-fire.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-06-musk-model-s-fire.html</guid>
      <description>After numerous reports and videos of a Telsa Model S being on fire at the end of a highway off-ramp, Telsa C.E.O. Elon Musk commented on the company blog:
 The Model S owner was nonetheless able to exit the highway as instructed by the onboard alert system, bring the car to a stop and depart the vehicle without injury. [&amp;hellip;] For consumers concerned about fire risk, there should be absolutely zero doubt that it is safer to power a car with a battery than a large tank of highly flammable liquid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empire&#39;s Definitive History of The West Wing</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-09-the-west-wing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-09-the-west-wing.html</guid>
      <description>Empire has a great collection of interviews and photographs from The West Wing. I particularly liked this little bit from Martin Sheen, talking about creator Aaron Sorkin:
 SHEEN: Aaron&amp;rsquo;s very sticky about using precise language. It&amp;rsquo;s in his contract: you have to use what he writes! It was poetry couched in politics, but it was poetry for the common man. It made us feel that our thoughts and our emotions and our hopes and fears could be expressed in a more lofty way and be no less human.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engaged</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-06-03-engaged.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-06-03-engaged.html</guid>
      <description>Two years ago I started writing emails to my future fiance. Two days ago I gave her those messages as I proposed we spend the rest of our lives together. Emily is truly the most amazing young woman I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had the pleasure of knowing, and I&amp;rsquo;m beyond blessed that God got us together.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank everyone who reached out over Facebook, on the phone, and in person to congratulate us both on this next step towards marriage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exams</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-30-exams.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-30-exams.html</guid>
      <description>Due to exams and the impending graduation speech I need to finish, KDHQ will be on hiatus the remainder of this week. Feel free to browse the archives, and don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to shoot me any questions or comments via email and Twitter. Thanks for reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Acquires Oculus VR</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-25-facebook-buys-oculus.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-25-facebook-buys-oculus.html</guid>
      <description>To the tune of $2 billion, Facebook has acquired virtual reality and headset maker, Oculus VR. From the Facebook Newsroom:
 Facebook today announced that it has reached a definitive agreement to acquire Oculus VR, Inc., the leader in immersive virtual reality technology, for a total of approximately $2 billion. [&amp;hellip;]
  While the applications for virtual reality technology beyond gaming are in their nascent stages, several industries are already experimenting with the technology, and Facebook plans to extend Oculus&amp;rsquo; existing advantage in gaming to new verticals, including communications, media and entertainment, education and other areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Launches &#34;Nearby Friends&#34;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-17-facebook-nearby-friends.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-17-facebook-nearby-friends.html</guid>
      <description>Very similar to Apple&amp;rsquo;s Find My Friends app, but powered by your existing Facebook network. The feature is explicitly opt-in, which should help placate some of the, inevitable, privacy-focused backlash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Plans to Introduce Auto-Playing Video</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-14-fb-auto-play-video.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-14-fb-auto-play-video.html</guid>
      <description>Emil Protalinski, writing for The Next Web:
 Facebook today introduced 15-second video ads, which will start playing without sound as they appear on screen and stop if you scroll past. If you tap the video, it will expand into a full-screen view with sound. The company says users can expect to start seeing these new ads &amp;ldquo;over the next few months.&amp;rdquo;
 Facebook is not the first to bring auto-play videos to mobile devices — both Instagram and Vine did the same last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Reactions</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-30-facebookreactions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-30-facebookreactions.html</guid>
      <description>Sarah Frier, reporting for Bloomberg Businessweek, wrote an excellent profile on Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Chief Product Officer Chris Cox and upcoming Facebook Reactions. In addition to profiling Cox, Frier also underscores the whole story with Cox&amp;rsquo;s latest project: Facebook Reactions—an attempt to extend the ubiquitous and iconic blue thumbs-up:
 The like button is the engine of Facebook and its most recognized symbol. A giant version of it adorns the entrance to the company’s campus in Menlo Park, Calif.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiftyfootshadows.net iOS 7 Parallax Wallpaper Pack</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-06-fiftyfoodshadows-ios-7-prallax-wallpaper-pack.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-06-fiftyfoodshadows-ios-7-prallax-wallpaper-pack.html</guid>
      <description>John Carey:
 Well, it took me a little longer than I had expected but here we go. The fiftyfootshadows parallax wallpaper pack for iOS devices running iOS 7. After quite a bit of research and trial and error I have settled on what I believe to be the optimal resolutions for iOS 7. Barring any major changes these images should leave you set for a good long while.
 Carey has two sets of 30 images (for iPad and iPhone) available right now on his post for free, and he&amp;rsquo;s also got 100-image collections for each device available at just $7 apiece, or $10 if you want both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firewatch launches tomorrow on PS4, Windows, Mac, and Linux for $19.99</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-firewatch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-firewatch.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to this game for two years, and it&amp;rsquo;s almost here. I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the reviews that get released today, but I&amp;rsquo;ll omit anything from my commentary or the pull-quotes that might spoil unreleased details about the game.
For the unaware, Firewatch is the first game from Panic-backed game studio, Campo Santo. Aside from the art style, which looks incredible, I&amp;rsquo;m most excited to work my way through the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firewatch Review</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-18-firewatch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-18-firewatch.html</guid>
      <description>Firewatch is a short game. It only takes a couple of hours to play through, and there isn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of replayability. Over the course of three days, an hour or two a night, my wife and I played Firewatch to completion.
We purchased and played Firewatch on our PS4. At times, I noticed small performance dips, particularly in areas with an overabundance of trees (sigh, foliage), but those moments were few and far between, and I&amp;rsquo;ve read that a future patch will address performance issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firewatch, Gretzky, and the Game of Go</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-28-briefing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-28-briefing.html</guid>
      <description>Apple: 1 Billion Active devices. Apple is huge and getting bigger. Federico Viticci at MacStories has the full coverage.
Panic: 2015 Report. In the latest iteration of their excellent annual reports, Cabel Sasser for Panic unpacks many aspects of being a small software shop and the challenges with it. The whole report is just great, but two bits caught my eye: 1.) Firewatch, Panic&amp;rsquo;s first major video game (developed by Campo Santo), gets released in two weeks, and 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitbit HR Review Transcript</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-09-fitbit-hr-review.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-09-fitbit-hr-review.html</guid>
      <description>The Fitbit HR is a good fitness tracker. It&amp;rsquo;s comfortable, has acceptable battery life, and the software is easy to use. Although the Fitbit HR device only shows your information, the accompanying app can show aggregated data from your friends, which provides passive, and surprisingly compelling, encouragement to log a few extra hundred steps.
Dr. Christopher B. Durr and I wanted to record a review of our Fitbit HRs, but we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find time to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folded heart</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-09-17-folded-heart.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-09-17-folded-heart.html</guid>
      <description>Every day, once I get back from classes, I go through all the loose papers that I accumulated for that day and organize them into spiral notebooks according to their subject. Because I rarely have time to do this in class, I often fold the papers I receive in half so they better fit into the pockets of my bag.
A couple days ago, however, I changed the way I fold these papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foolish Reporting of the Week: Brad Reed</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-19-foolish-bgr.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-19-foolish-bgr.html</guid>
      <description>Brad Reed, writing for BGR, wins this week&amp;rsquo;s Foolish Reporting award for his ridiculously misleading headline writing. The headline in question? &amp;ldquo;iPhone user hates iOS 7 so much that he&amp;rsquo;s suing Apple over it&amp;rdquo;:
 Brighter colors and flat icons just aren&amp;rsquo;t for everybody. That said, it seems that iPhone user Mark Menacher hates them much more than anyone else. CNET reports that Menacher has actually filed a suit against Apple in small claims court and is asking the company to let him remove the iOS 7 install file from his iOS devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Football as Football</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-19-football-as-football.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-19-football-as-football.html</guid>
      <description>American football logos redesigned for European football clubs. Easily one of the best sites I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this month — I particularly love the Browns&amp;rsquo;s badge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For $15, Firewatch for PC will develop and ship your in-game photos</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-firewatch-photos.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-firewatch-photos.html</guid>
      <description>John Walker, writing for Rock Paper Shotgun:
 At a certain point you find a disposable cardboard camera with most of its film still available, and are encouraged by Delilah to take some snaps of anything you find interesting. And it’s worth doing so, because as well as a nice little surprise toward the end, once you’ve filled your film a menu option becomes available to have them processed and delivered to your real-world house as glossy photographs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frank Chimero&#39;s New Personal Website</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-04-fc-new-site.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-04-fc-new-site.html</guid>
      <description>Frank Chimero, one of the veterans of web design and a personal hero of mine, just took the wraps off his new website:
 So, here we are: aesthetics, content, and purpose all lined up. Make it colorful, make it boxy, make it a little cluttered. Fill it with things that you love, and for god’s sake, Frank, get all of your stuff in one place so people can find it, and you can feel a bit of pride about the things you’ve made and collected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Front page design</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-01-06-front-page.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-01-06-front-page.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with how best to structure the front page of sites that have a focus on writing. The front page is the first impression, a digital handshake, and ensuring it conveys your content in a way you want is extremely important.
A number of different conventions exist for listing news-related content. However, most styles are based on one of two ways:
 Present a list of all the posts, much like an archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Front page design 2</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-01-14-front-page-pt-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-01-14-front-page-pt-2.html</guid>
      <description>Following my post on [The Front Page]({% post_url 2014-01-06-front-page %}), I had a good email conversation with my buddy, Nick Heer. Our conversation brought up some more ideas regarding page design, and I wanted to expand on them here. Consider this post as part of an ongoing, public discussion and exploration of rhetorical design for the front page of a news and journalistic website.
Visitor Accessible Post Data The following components can be found in nearly every text-based document (post, article, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating graphs with Processing</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-05-06-generating-graphs-with-processing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-05-06-generating-graphs-with-processing.html</guid>
      <description>Ben Barry&amp;rsquo;s post on designing the 2011 Facebook f8 Conference remains one of my favorite pieces about design on the internet. As I was reading back through it the other day, I came across how Barry had gone about generating those signature Facebook graph images.
 While working on f8 2010 we developed a rudimentary Processing script that allowed us to generate graph imagery. For 2011 we dusted it off and polished it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get FROGED</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-01-12-get-froged.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-01-12-get-froged.html</guid>
      <description>In college, trying to fully rely on God every day is hard.
It&amp;rsquo;s our first real venture into the world and the need for us to be self-sufficient is overbearing. So much so, that we often forget to rely on Him to get us through. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget to pray when we have homework, or substitute quiet time of reflection for hanging out with friends, but none of these things help us grow spiritually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub&#39;s New Text Editor: Atom</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-26-atom.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-26-atom.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in my text editor all day. So when a new player enters the field, I take notice and evaluate what it brings to the table over my current setup. Today, GitHub, the social code-sharing website, announced the arrival of Atom.io — a text editor they&amp;rsquo;ve been building for around six years.
Unlike my current editor (Sublime Text), Atom is billed as &amp;ldquo;a desktop application based on web technologies,&amp;rdquo; which means that the main interface is driven by a web-rendering engine, unlike most existing text editors today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Your Resume A Face Lift</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-19-chanpory-resume.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-19-chanpory-resume.html</guid>
      <description>Wow. Even though this post from Chanpory Rith dates back to 2006, his advice is still incredibly practical for the job seekers of today. A must read for anyone who&amp;rsquo;s looking to create their own resume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving up 30% to Sell In-App iOS Subscriptions</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-21-beats-in-app.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-21-beats-in-app.html</guid>
      <description>Peter Kafka, writing for Re/code:
 Beats updated its iPhone app today, and now lets users subscribe to the $10 a month service from within the app, using iTunes&amp;rsquo; billing system. That means Beats, and the music labels that license their stuff to the service, will give up $3 a month on every subscription sold through iTunes.
 Beats Music is willing to take a 30% hit just to sell their same subscription, but through an in-app purchase dialog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoDaddy to File for IPO</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-14-godaddy-ipo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-14-godaddy-ipo.html</guid>
      <description>Telis Demos and Mike Spector for the Wall Street Journal, reporting on the possibility of a GoDaddy IPO coming later this year:
 The Scottsdale, Ariz., company, which provides domain-name registration and website-hosting services to more than 12 million customers world-wide, in the coming weeks plans to interview banks that would lead the underwriting of its IPO, the people said. Based on a typical IPO time frame, the company&amp;rsquo;s shares could begin trading in the second half of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye, Editorially</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-16-goodbye-editorially.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-16-goodbye-editorially.html</guid>
      <description>Editorially, the collaborative online writing application, is shutting down on May 30. From their Goodbye post:
 We’re proud of the team and tool that we built together and incredibly thankful that so many of you were willing to give it a try. And we continue to believe that evolving the way we collaborate as writers and editors is important work. But Editorially has failed to attract enough users to be sustainable, and we cannot honestly say we have reason to expect that to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye, Facebook</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-02-02-byebye-facebook.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-02-02-byebye-facebook.html</guid>
      <description>It started with one text from my girlfriend. The message read:
 byebye facebook
 Strong words coming from her, but I got excited. Leaving Facebook was an idea I have been toying with for quite a while now, but never had the motivation to actually do. Here now was my opportunity, and I decided to take it it.
There were some real reasons for keeping my profile active, namely that I am the sole admin/developer for several pages and applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Buys Nest for $3.2 Billion</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-13-google-buys-nest.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-13-google-buys-nest.html</guid>
      <description>Google announced today that they had just paid $3.2 billion in cash to acquire Nest, the makers of those [gorgeous thermostats]({% post_url 2013-10-08-the-nest-protect %}) and smoke detectors. This acquisition is interesting for two reasons:
 Tony Fadell, Nest CEO and ex-Senior Vice President of the iPod Division at Apple, now works for Google. Google now has a hand in the personal home safety game.  My gut reaction is that Google is looking for new ways into the home, and buying Nest was a great way to open the door.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google death results</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-12-08-google-death-results.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-12-08-google-death-results.html</guid>
      <description>I was introspective this morning, and found myself Googling about death. I ran across this comic by xkcd, got inspired and ended up collecting quite a bit of data about the number of search results Google gives back for any given age of death. I&amp;rsquo;ve put those results into a graph for your pleasure, and you can also download the spreadsheet data in .xls if you like.

Download the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Releases &#34;Web Designer&#34;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-01-google-web-designer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-01-google-web-designer.html</guid>
      <description>It would be much more honest if they called it Google Ad Designer. Google needed a way to help designers make HTML5-based advertisements, and this is their solution.
I understand wanting to help create good web ads, but I&amp;rsquo;m curious why Web Designer doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like any of the company&amp;rsquo;s other applications. Most of Google&amp;rsquo;s recent designs have shared a consistent language, as noted by Farhad Manjoo of Fast Company:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Hangouts App Can Now Make Phone Calls</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-19-google-hangouts-ios-update.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-19-google-hangouts-ios-update.html</guid>
      <description>Google recently updated their Hangouts app on iOS to include the ability to make phone calls within the U.S. and Canada for free. However, the most interesting new feature is you can now make and receive calls in Hangouts if you have a Google Voice number. This should provide much-needed relief for anyone who&amp;rsquo;s had to use the abysmal &amp;ldquo;Google Voice&amp;rdquo; app to manage their Google-given number.
The update to Hangouts also offers a peek into Google&amp;rsquo;s long-term strategy for iOS:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GORUCK GR1</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-04-23-goruck-gr1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-04-23-goruck-gr1.html</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s now been a year and a half since I first received my GORUCK GR1 rucksack. Unlike an app or new piece of technology, a bag like this needs months of thorough use before a true opinion can be formed.
However, I don&amp;rsquo;t want this being called a review of the GR1 — I have yet to take this bag to the limits of its advertised durability and strength. That being said, this bag has suffered through the type of lifestyle my gear has to put up with — one that includes: muddy soccer boots and sweaty gear; trudging through rain and snow; and being tossed into trunks, onto car floors and skidded across asphalt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grocery Shopping from Home</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-09-amazon-dash.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-09-amazon-dash.html</guid>
      <description>Amazon Dash is a new device that lets you scan the barcode on household items and have them added to your online Amazon.com or AmazonFresh shopping cart. The idea is that, as you are running low, you scan your cereal, milk, and paper towels — all of which will then be shipped to your door in a few days.
Amazon Dash is currently only available by &amp;ldquo;invitation only,&amp;rdquo; and it is unclear if it requires an AmazonFresh account, which is only open to residents of Seattle, San Francisco, or Southern California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habit building</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-30-habit-building.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-30-habit-building.html</guid>
      <description>Update: this post was written over on a Wordpress blog I had during the summer. Although I migrated most of the posts to my current setup, some are written with the implication that they&amp;rsquo;re still over there - silly things.
I&amp;rsquo;m just going to warn you, this will probably be a little rough for the first couple weeks. I typically write longer, thought-out posts over on kyledreger.com, and never felt that short entries should fill the archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Easter!</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-18-easter.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-18-easter.html</guid>
      <description>Just a small note: KDHQ will be shutting down this Saturday and Sunday in celebration of the Easter weekend. Posting will resume on Monday.
A happy Easter to all my readers and their families. Enjoy the weekend, and God bless!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hemingway: Write Bold and Clear</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-12-hemingway.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-12-hemingway.html</guid>
      <description>Hemingway, developed by Adam and Ben Long, is a small website where you can have your text analyzed against a variety of clarity-focused metrics. From the home page:
 Hemingway highlights long, complex sentences and common errors; if you see a yellow highlight, shorten the sentence or split it. If you see a red highlight, your sentence is so dense and complicated that your readers will get lost trying to follow its meandering, splitting logic — try editing this sentence to remove the red.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homescreen for October 2015</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-09-29-october-homescreen.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-09-29-october-homescreen.html</guid>
      <description>Folders on top. Alphabetize everything. Never have four apps in the dock.
Grab the wallpaper from Unsplash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoodies</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-02-19-hoodies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-02-19-hoodies.html</guid>
      <description>I love them. Hooded sweatshirts, or &amp;ldquo;hoodies&amp;rdquo;, are one of my favorite pieces of clothing. Whenever I get a hoodie, I&amp;rsquo;ll wear it until the fabric is begging to be thrown away. I love the simple colors and pulling the sleeves up when you sit down to type. I enjoy trying to make the drawstrings perfectly symmetrical. Eventually, however, I almost always end up pulling that string out.
They&amp;rsquo;re versatile, able to be worn through the winter and on cool summer nights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Animate a Photo, The 2.5D Effect</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-22-animate-a-photo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-22-animate-a-photo.html</guid>
      <description>Joe Fellows, the founder of Make Productions (a short film and production company), shows how he creates the effect of motion in still photographs, a la parallax. The whole process, from photo shoot to post-production, is fascinating, and the end result is undeniably mesmerizing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Be Right Most of the Time</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-02-bezos-right.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-02-bezos-right.html</guid>
      <description>Jason Fried, writing about Amazon CEO, Jeff Bezos:
 He’s [Bezos&amp;rsquo;] observed that the smartest people are constantly revising their understanding, reconsidering a problem they thought they’d already solved. They’re open to new points of view, new information, new ideas, contradictions, and challenges to their own way of thinking.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Vepser 1.007</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-03-how-to-make-a-vesper.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-03-how-to-make-a-vesper.html</guid>
      <description>Dave Wiskus put together a fantastic post about the design decisions behind the latest iOS 7 update to, my [personal favorite note-taking app]({% post_url 2013-07-13-vesper %}), Vesper:
 Rather than merely slap a fresh coat of paint on things, we wanted to take the same approach we did with 1.0 and really think through the state of iOS. Which decisions did we agree with? What did we think still needed improvement?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTC Releases the HTC One (M8)</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-26-htc-one-m8.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-26-htc-one-m8.html</guid>
      <description>A larger, faster, and longer-lasting version of the original HTC One.
David Pierce, writing for The Verge, has a lot of really good things to say about HTC&amp;rsquo;s newest model, and it seems that this iteration fixes most of the issues that users bemoaned about in the previous design. Sadly, however, the One&amp;rsquo;s camera still stinks compared to the competition, and HTC continues to plaster their &amp;ldquo;Sense&amp;rdquo; UI over Android, which often makes things look worse instead of better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Need a Popcorn Button</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-03-shekey-microwave.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-03-shekey-microwave.html</guid>
      <description>Aaron Shekey, a designer and developer living in Minneapolis, recently remodeled his kitchen, which gave him the opportunity to take a look at the current state of design amid various home appliances:
 In my frustration I discovered that all I wanted from a microwave was a single knob. That’s it. I want to open a carefully considered door, close it without waking the neighbors, twist a single knob to the desired time, press it to start, and hear a single chime when it’s done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I lost my iPhone</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-10-24-lost-iphone.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-10-24-lost-iphone.html</guid>
      <description>Fun little thing that happened to me today:
Was walking in the library when I went to grab my iPhone, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t in my pocket. I checked my bag and laptop case, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t there either. I started to freak out a bit. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a passcode set and thinking of how many websites it was authenticated with made me sweat.
I quickly went to a computer, logged on to iCloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iA Writer 3.0</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-09-15-writer-three-point-oh.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-09-15-writer-three-point-oh.html</guid>
      <description>iA:
 If you came here to read about ground-breaking new features, we have to apologize: iA Writer has not become bigger. It has become lighter, smarter, more refined.
 What a great way to phrase the changes in this update. It&amp;rsquo;s refreshing to see an app remove features, while still moving towards their original goal: a minimalistic writing experience.
I&amp;rsquo;m also happy to see that there is, once again, a single version iA Writer, rather than the Regular / Pro variants they had before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iconic: A Photographic Tribute to Apple Innovation</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-07-iconic-apple-tribute.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-07-iconic-apple-tribute.html</guid>
      <description>A six-chapter photo book depicting every product Apple has ever made. From the product page:
 Iconic uses vivid color and detail to document Apple&amp;rsquo;s journey in design, form and function — and looks back at over 35 years of Apple innovation. Four years in the making, the author captured over 150,000 photos of nearly every product Apple has made, including rare prototypes and even packaging.
 It&amp;rsquo;s everything you&amp;rsquo;d want in a coffee table book about Apple gear: lots of pictures and unobtrusive captions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iMessage Woes Continue</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-24-imessage-woes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-24-imessage-woes.html</guid>
      <description>Over at Re/code, Ina Fried sheds some more light on [that nasty bug in iMessage]({% post_url 2014-05-13-imessage %}):
 iMessage relies on Apple’s messaging system to intercept a text message sent to another iOS device and re-routes it through its servers rather than sending it via the wireless carriers as a standard SMS or MMS message.
  The benefits of iMessage include bypassing a wireless carrier’s text messaging charges, enabling the ability to tell when a message is read or delivered and to send a message simultaneously to all of one’s iOS and Mac devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InstantClick.js</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-10-instantclick-js.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-10-instantclick-js.html</guid>
      <description>Incredibly smart JavaScript library from Alex Dieulot that uses the HTML5 pushState() spec to pre-load whichever link a user is currently hovering over. From the InstantClick homepage:
 Latency is inevitable with today’s internet architecture so InstantClick cheats by preloading links you are likely to click on.
  Before a visitor clicks on a link, he hovers over that link. Between these two events, 200 ms to 300 ms usually pass by (test yourself here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Loren Brichter</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-28-brichter-letterpress-interview.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-28-brichter-letterpress-interview.html</guid>
      <description>After [noticing that Letterpress had been sold to Solebon LLC][me], I reached out to Atebit&amp;rsquo;s founder and sole proprietor, Loren Brichter. After we waited a few weeks to let things settle down, Mr. Brichter agreed to do a small interview over email. What follows is our conversation about selling Letterpress, iOS, and developing on the web.
 K.Q. Dreger: Hello, Loren. Thanks for agreeing to do this interview. I&amp;rsquo;ll cut right to the chase: Why decide to sell Letterpress?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewing as research</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-02-01-interviewing-as-research.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-02-01-interviewing-as-research.html</guid>
      <description>For my English class, we are working on writing a profile based on an interview we have conducted with an individual. This is a new form of investigation for me, I&amp;rsquo;m use to doing my own static research on a subject, curating the good from the bad and then polishing the result into something someone would maybe want to read. It&amp;rsquo;s been the same process since high school.
With writing a profile, it&amp;rsquo;s different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS 7.0.3 Released with Faster Transitions</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-23-ios-7-patch-3-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-23-ios-7-patch-3-released.html</guid>
      <description>Quietly shipped alongside all that was released on Tuesday, iOS 7.0.3 is now available for download.
In addition to iCloud Keychain, which lets you sync your passwords between iOS devices, Apple has also addressed complaints regarding the system-wide parallax effects. Federico Viticci for MacStories:
 Apple has listened, and in iOS 7.0.3 the Reduce Motion setting (available in General &amp;gt; Accessibility) now truly reduces animations: switching to apps and back to Home screen, unlocking the device, and moving between folders is now a cross-fade that is much faster than Apple’s animations with Reduce Motion turned off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone Pre-Orders Top 4 Million in 24 Hours</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-15-iphone-pre-orders.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-15-iphone-pre-orders.html</guid>
      <description>Apple PR:
 Apple today announced a record number of first day pre-orders of iPhone 6 and iPhone 6 Plus, the biggest advancements in iPhone history, with over four million in the first 24 hours. Demand for the new iPhones exceeds the initial pre-order supply and while a significant amount will be delivered to customers beginning on Friday and throughout September, many iPhone pre-orders are scheduled to be delivered in October.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeff Bezos will Pay You $5k to Quit Working at Amazon</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-11-amazon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-11-amazon.html</guid>
      <description>Jeff Bezos, in his annual letter to shareholders of Amazon:
 [The program] is called Pay to Quit. It was invented by the clever people at Zappos, and the Amazon fulfillment centers have been iterating on it. Pay to Quit is pretty simple. Once a year, we offer to pay our associates to quit. The first year the offer is made, it’s for $2,000. Then it goes up one thousand dollars a year until it reaches $5,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Mayer: Someday I&#39;ll Fly</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-30-john-mayer-someday-ill-fly.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-30-john-mayer-someday-ill-fly.html</guid>
      <description>Eastwood Allen:
 Someday I&amp;rsquo;ll Fly chronicles the musical evolution of one of the most influential solo artists of his generation. Featuring rare demos, interviews and live performances; it is told in it&amp;rsquo;s entirety from Mayer&amp;rsquo;s perspective.
This is a fan-made, nonprofit documentary that utilises archived television interviews, podcasts, bootleg recordings, Internet clips, album tracks, DVD and Blu-ray footage in an effort to showcase John Mayer&amp;rsquo;s career in music.
 This fan-made documentary is one of the best documentaries I&amp;rsquo;ve ever watched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerbal Space Program</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-07-17-cbd-kerbal-space-program.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-07-17-cbd-kerbal-space-program.html</guid>
      <description>By guest editor, Christopher B. Durr.
 We choose to go to the moon in this decade and do the other things, not because they are easy, but because they are hard —John F. Kennedy
 This famous quote by Jack is one of my favorites and one that I think we often forget to remember. President Kennedy, of course, was talking about what would become the U.S. space program. A program that involved strapping human beings to giant stacks of fuel and launching them 230,000+ miles away from home, in a time when computers were the size of rooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letterpress now owned by Solebon LLC</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-letterpress-solebon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-letterpress-solebon.html</guid>
      <description>In non-Firewatch related news, it appears that Letterpress, a critically-acclaimed iOS word game from Loren Brichter&amp;rsquo;s Atebits, is now under the ownership of Solebon LLC.
Letterpress, which got updated to version 1.6 today, now lists Solebon LLC as the seller, and the official Letterpress website has been updated to reflect this change in ownership:
 Letterpress® is now part of the Solebon family!
  The Solebon team will be working on many fronts over the next few months to evolve Letterpress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is a Game</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-10-life-is-a-game.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-10-life-is-a-game.html</guid>
      <description>Oliver Emberton on his personal blog:
 You might not realise, but real life is a game of strategy. There are some fun mini-games – like dancing, driving, running, and sex – but the key to winning is simply managing your resources.
  Most importantly, successful players put their time into the right things. Later in the game money comes into play, but your top priority should always be mastering where your time goes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lionel Messi&#39;s Improbability</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-11-impossible-messi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-11-impossible-messi.html</guid>
      <description>If you love football, statistics, and graphs, do I have something for you. Benjamin Morris, writing for FiveThirtyEight, analyzes the astonishing career, and numbers, of Lionel Messi:
 In other words, if Barca-Messi and Argentina-Messi were two different people, even based solely on the stats recorded since 2010, there’s a good chance they’d be the two best players in the world.
 Not enough? Proof, proof, and more (albeit annoying music) proof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Stream of Today&#39;s Apple Event</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-22-apple-special-event-stream.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-22-apple-special-event-stream.html</guid>
      <description>For the first in a very long time, Apple has a live stream of today&amp;rsquo;s event available. However, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a Mac, iOS device, or Apple TV to catch it:
 Live Streaming video requires Safari 4 or later on OS X v10.6 or later; Safari on iOS 4.2 or later. Streaming via Apple TV requires second- or third-generation Apple TV with software 5.0.2 or later.
 If you don&amp;rsquo;t meet the requirements, definitely check out liveblogs from The Verge, Macworld, and Engadget for the latest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Cabbies Don&#39;t Need GPS</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-22-london-cabs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-22-london-cabs.html</guid>
      <description>Roff Smith, writing for National Geographic, in an excellent feature about a test that all London cabbies have to pass. It&amp;rsquo;s a long read, but the whole thing is incredibly fascinating:
 To qualify for that elusive green badge, you need to learn by heart all 320 sample runs that are listed in the Blue Book, the would-be cabbie&amp;rsquo;s bible. You will also have to commit to memory the 25,000 streets, roads, avenues, courts, lanes, crescents, places, mews, yards, hills, and alleys that lie within a six-mile radius of Charing Cross.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looping with Liquid</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-09-liquid-looping.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-09-liquid-looping.html</guid>
      <description>In my podcast.xml file, I have a loop that goes through all my posts and identifies which ones are episodes of The Log:
{% highlight ruby %} for post in site.posts limit:10 if post.layout == &amp;lsquo;post-log&amp;rsquo; # Do cool loopy stuff {% endhighlight %}
This was working great, but I began to notice that only the latest two episodes of The Log were being displayed on its iTunes page. I spent about an hour searching the web, before I realized my mistake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lovingly Crafted</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-10-02-paying-for-software.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-10-02-paying-for-software.html</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re building a chair.
But this isn&amp;rsquo;t a normal, buy-one-at-the-retail-store kind of chair. Your chair is going to be quality, made of the best materials you can afford, and take months to finish.
You work a little each day to design, measure, cut, sand, test, stain, let dry, and prepare the chair for sale. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve finished, you carefully load the chair into the car and drive off to your store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Desks</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-13-mac-desks.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-13-mac-desks.html</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ll want to rearrange your workspace after seeing these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mactracker.app</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-23-mactracker.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-23-mactracker.html</guid>
      <description>Writing my last post, I was trying to remember the name of an app I had used that listed the details and specifications of not just every Mac, but also every Apple device ever made. A little searching and I finally found it: Mactracker by Ian Page.
Page has versions of Mactracker available for OS X and iOS, and both versions are completely free. This is a fantastic little app, and it provides a great way to look at Apple&amp;rsquo;s history of products, in entirety, from the beginning to the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Made on an iPhone</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-04-made-on-an-iphone.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-04-made-on-an-iphone.html</guid>
      <description>Apple, on their new &amp;ldquo;1.24.14 Film&amp;rdquo; page:
 On January 24, 1984, Apple introduced the Macintosh. And with it a promise that the power of technology, put in the hands of everyone, could change the world. On January 24, 2014, we sent 15 camera crews all over the world to show how that promise has become a reality.
 The whole video was shot using the iPhone 5s&amp;rsquo; built-in camera, compiled on a Mac, and then scored with an original soundtrack — in one day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margins</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-03-the-margins.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-03-the-margins.html</guid>
      <description>Hello, again. Craig Mod, in a beautifully-written piece:
 Reach for a book. The dedication and earnestness of those who made it is revealed immediately in the margins. If the margins feel questionable, be suspicious. Other corners were likely cut. All authors should have a Margin Clause in their contracts. Objection, your honor. Never be fooled by a fancy cover. Always remember: Covers are just there to protect pages with beautiful margins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mavericks Detects Movement to Delay OS X Sleep</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-01-mavericks-ambient-detection.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-01-mavericks-ambient-detection.html</guid>
      <description>Neat feature of Mavericks that prevents the machine from going to sleep if it detects a change in ambient lighting, regardless of the current idle time.
Reminds me of how Macbook LEDs would, while asleep, pulse at the rate of a resting-adult&amp;rsquo;s respiratory rhythm. Delight is in the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mavericks Update for Mail.app and Gmail</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-09-mavericks-gmail-update.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-09-mavericks-gmail-update.html</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve recently upgraded to OS X Mavericks and found that Mail.app was a doing an increasingly-poor job at managing your mail, I encourage you to go download this patch from Apple which fixes those issues.
Between the popularity of Gmail and Mail.app being a core OS X application, I really can&amp;rsquo;t believe they didn&amp;rsquo;t catch these issues in the beta releases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maybe a love story</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-11-17-maybe-a-love-story.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-11-17-maybe-a-love-story.html</guid>
      <description>(The following is, if you will, unstructured poetry - I have no idea what it means, even though I wrote it.)
There once was a story about love, but that story wasn&amp;rsquo;t ever published. It was a story in the sense that it had a beginning and middle, but, notably, it lacked an end. There was a main character, the protagonist, and many obstacles for him, or was it a her, to overcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Keyboards</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-03-01-mechanical-keyboards.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-03-01-mechanical-keyboards.html</guid>
      <description>Ah, keyboards. They are the most intimate form of connection we have with our computers. However, for the past couple years, I have given little thought to what actually goes into making a good keyboard.
Aside from the built-in keyboard on my laptop, I have only used several other types of external keyboards. The first few were those that were bundled with any PC &amp;ldquo;package&amp;rdquo; you could purchase at the local Best Buy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medium now supports RSS</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-05-superfeedr-medium-rss.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-05-superfeedr-medium-rss.html</guid>
      <description>Julien Genestoux, founder of recently-acquired-by-Medium Superfeedr, on enabling full-content RSS for Medium publications and users:
 As we want the open web to remain strong, we were delighted to find that the folks at Medium share the same values. And we think that Superfeedr&amp;rsquo;s acquisition is a powerful indicator of Medium&amp;rsquo;s support for open protocols. As an example of this, my first commit at Medium was to enable full content RSS feeds both for publications and users (available in your settings).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memberships</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/members.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/members.html</guid>
      <description>Membership Information
A membership to kyledreger.com is the best way to help support this site and my writing. It is important to note that membership is not required to view any of the content on this site (that stuff will always be free), but I have created some perks for those who do take the plunge:
Price: $2.25 a month
Become a member of kyledreger.com Existing member login — Contact</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Employee Badge Redesign</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-18-new-ms-badge.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-18-new-ms-badge.html</guid>
      <description>Ahmet Alp Balkan recently posted his redesign of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s employee badge or &amp;ldquo;Blue Badge.&amp;rdquo; Balkan:
 It’s over a year Microsoft has started to rebrand itself, starting from its logo to a brand new looking OS, from campus shuttles to direction signs on the campus and so on. Many employees are wearing this badge on their belts or pockets every day. So why not redesign this good ol’ beast?
 A nice premise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing Brands</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-03-minimal-brands.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-03-minimal-brands.html</guid>
      <description>Mehmet Gozetlik, the founder of design collective Antrepo, has taken 17 well-known brands and reduced their products&amp;rsquo; branding to the bare minimal. Although I think consumers would quickly tire of everything being set in Helvetica, I do like how Gozetlik favored printing directly on the glass or plastic instead of using a paper wrapper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mojosoft</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-15-minecraft-microsoft.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-15-minecraft-microsoft.html</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has acquired Mojang, the company behind Minecraft:
 The Mojang team will join Microsoft Studios, which includes the studios behind global blockbuster franchises “Halo,” “Forza,” “Fable” and more. Microsoft’s investments in cloud and mobile technologies will enable “Minecraft” players to benefit from richer and faster worlds, more powerful development tools, and more opportunities to connect across the “Minecraft” community.
  Microsoft plans to continue to make “Minecraft” available across all the platforms on which it is available today: PC, iOS, Android, Xbox and PlayStation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mom</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-11-12-mom.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-11-12-mom.html</guid>
      <description>You wake up to the sound of your daily alarm. It&amp;rsquo;s 6:25 a.m. — another day of work. It&amp;rsquo;s not too hot, so you put on a long sleeve button-up and a nice pair of khakis. You&amp;rsquo;re glad that you washed everything last night. Throwing your lunch in your bag, you drive off to work.
20 minutes later, you&amp;rsquo;re at your desk. You smile as you text good morning to your new fiancee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSNBC Has Bieber Fever</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-24-msnbc-has-bieber-fever.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-24-msnbc-has-bieber-fever.html</guid>
      <description>In the middle of an interview with Congresswoman Jane Harman about the NSA, MSNBC reporter Andrea Mitchell interrupts the congresswoman mid-sentence to switch over to the &amp;ldquo;Breaking News&amp;rdquo; that Justin Bieber had been arrested for a DUI.
It&amp;rsquo;s not often you see The Onion get beat to the punch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Apps and Home Screen</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-27-my-apps-and-home-screen.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-09-27-my-apps-and-home-screen.html</guid>
      <description>You can tell a lot about a person by looking at how they set up their home screen and apps. This is mine as it currently stands on my iPhone 4:
My home screen is a little more sparse than others, but this allows me to quickly get on and off my phone [without getting too distracted]({% post_url 2013-09-26-kraus-distraction %}).
The Home Screen  The wallpaper is courtesy of Bradley Casteneda, who has some real beautiful shots that fit perfectly with iOS 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Frozen Yogurt Recipe</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-12-22-froyo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-12-22-froyo.html</guid>
      <description>After countless trial and error, I have finally settled on, what I believe to be, the best frozen yogurt recipe. If you enjoy vanilla and a good cup of coffee, try this out:
Ingredients  Base layer of low-fat Vanilla yogurt Sprinkle with chipped mints 3-5 crushed espresso beans 1-3 crushed raspberries Lightly top with caramel Vanilla cake batter Granola Broken up peanuts Kiwi  Instructions Start with a small base-layer of vanilla cake batter ice cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Mom&#39;s Motorcycle</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-06-19-my-moms-motorcycle.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-06-19-my-moms-motorcycle.html</guid>
      <description>Douglas Gautraud:
 This is a short film about how my mom became the owner of a motorcycle for the My Rode Reel competition. More deeply it is about how people use objects to connect with times, ideas, and people.
 Polished, funny, and creative non-fiction storytelling at its very finest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#39;s distraction</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-09-04-natures-distraction.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-09-04-natures-distraction.html</guid>
      <description>My girlfriend and I were recently sitting in the library doing homework when it began to rain outside. The sound of raindrops hitting the roof sounded like a roar of a jet engine right outside the nearby window. A couple of minutes later she asked me if I wanted to see a poem she had written for one of her literature classes. I liked it so much that I asked her for a copy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nest Protect: Your Smoke Alarm, but Beautiful</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-08-the-nest-protect.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-08-the-nest-protect.html</guid>
      <description>Nest, the company behind the gorgeous (yes, gorgeous) thermostat, just released their latest product: a smoke and carbon monoxide detector called the Nest Protect. Tony Fadell, C.E.O. of Nest and Apple alumni, on his company&amp;rsquo;s blog:
 It was never just about thermostats. At its core, Nest has always been about the home. We reinvent unloved home products to create simple, beautiful, thoughtful things. First we made an entirely different kind of thermostat, because saving energy should be easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Old Stock Photography</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-22-new-old-stock.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-22-new-old-stock.html</guid>
      <description>Cole Townsend has started curating a collection of vintage photography from public archives. All of the images are free of any known copyright.
Some of my favorites include this map of &amp;ldquo;New France&amp;rdquo;, people being people (resist the urge to think the middle gentleman is holding a phone), and a lettering grid that looks oddly similar to the one used in iOS 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site Search</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-27-site-search.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-27-site-search.html</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Scratch that, I&amp;rsquo;ve removed the search for now. Until I can find a way to search in-site without punching out to Google, I&amp;rsquo;ll go without.
One of my goals with this site is to aid in both the reading and discovery of my content. To that end, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a search form (powered by Google) to the navigation. Although I would prefer the search be powered by DuckDuckGo, they don&amp;rsquo;t have all my posts indexed, leading to incomplete search results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Habit</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-12-31-new-years-habit.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-12-31-new-years-habit.html</guid>
      <description>As I contemplate 2012, less than 12 hours away at this time, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about the New Year resolutions. While I was thinking, I read a post by Leo Babauta on Zen Habits about aiming to create new habits for the new year, rather than setting &amp;ldquo;resolutions&amp;rdquo;. While the article focused on health, there were universal comments about helping to create healthy habits and have them stick. I particularly like this part:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nike&#43; Move</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-04-nike-plus-move.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-04-nike-plus-move.html</guid>
      <description>Apple and Nike have always had a good relationship (remember the Nike + iPod Sport Kit?) so it&amp;rsquo;s little surprise that one of the first &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; apps to take advantage of the 5S&amp;rsquo;s new activity-monitoring M7 processor is from Nike.
I do wonder how much longer this relationship will last, however, given that Nike has a whole line of wrist wear designed to do the M7&amp;rsquo;s job without an iPhone. Things will get interesting if Apple ever does enter into the wearable-computing game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nintendo</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-22-nintendo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-22-nintendo.html</guid>
      <description>Nintendo recently said that it is heading towards a third consecutive annual loss, induced primarily by the weak sales of their latest console, the Wii U.
If you have followed Nintendo in the news at all the past couple weeks, you know that most news stories have read along the lines of, &amp;ldquo;Is it time for Nintendo to go mobile?&amp;rdquo; — insinuating that Nintendo needs to start pushing out games for iOS and Android if it wants to survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Man&#39;s Sky Just Went Gold</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-07-no-mans-sky-is-finished.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-07-no-mans-sky-is-finished.html</guid>
      <description>Big news from a tiny game studio, and a welcome announcement after hearing the June launch was delayed until August.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NPR&#39;s Text-Only Website</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-06-thin-npr.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-06-thin-npr.html</guid>
      <description>An alternative to the main, graphical version of NPR.org, and about 625x lighter (three separate, cache cleared refreshes have 1.3 Kb vs 813 Kb). More sites should offer something like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obama pledges $4 billion in funding for computer science education in schools</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-06-computer-science-in-education.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-06-computer-science-in-education.html</guid>
      <description>Davey Alba, reporting for Wired:
 Under the president’s plan, the Department of Education will divide the $4 billion over three years to states that propose well-designed five-year plans to increase computer science access in classrooms. Along with billions in federal funding, the initiative also includes commitments from philanthropists and some of the country’s largest tech companies to help increase opportunities for computer science training, especially for underrepresented groups.
 The medium is the message, and almost all of today&amp;rsquo;s messages are delivered through the medium of computational devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Removing the Headphone Jack</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-02-headphone-jack.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-02-headphone-jack.html</guid>
      <description>The Wall Street Journal reported two things: 1.) Apple will be moving to a two-year cycle for major iPhone hardware updates, and 2.) the next iPhone won&amp;rsquo;t have a headphone jack.
And then a majority of the tech press lost its mind. Not so much about the two-year thing, more about the ditching of a 50 year-old standard. It reminds me of when Steve Jobs put the nail in the coffin of Flash on iOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Shoulders of Giants</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-29-on-the-shoulders-of-giants.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-29-on-the-shoulders-of-giants.html</guid>
      <description>The very first website I ever designed was the horrifically-named Linkag3verywhere.com. I built it with the intention of displaying a curated list of links to online games, websites and articles I found interesting. I gave the address out to my cousins and friends, and remember being thrilled to see the (mostly generated directly by me) page visits go up every day. I still have the Linkag3verywhere.com code in a folder of archived projects, and every now and again I&amp;rsquo;ll go pull up the original design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One year</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-03-23-one-year.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-03-23-one-year.html</guid>
      <description>My best friend.It&amp;rsquo;s been one year since I started dating my girlfriend. She is my best friend, someone I confide in all the time and my spiritual support. I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget the day she invited me to coffee, our first date, and how I made sure to ask her back &amp;ldquo;same time, same place&amp;rdquo; the next day.
I could not have asked God for a better partner and I thank Him for her every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of Office</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-26-ecwca.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-26-ecwca.html</guid>
      <description>Due to unforeseeable internet conditions over the next few days, I&amp;rsquo;m putting KDHQ on break for March 27 through March 30.
At 8am tomorrow, I leave with a group of students to attend the East Central Writing Centers Association&amp;rsquo;s annual conference. I&amp;rsquo;ll be speaking on a panel, answering questions about how today&amp;rsquo;s writing and communication centers can offer better services to their students, with a focus on new technologies.
Aside from the conference itself, I am really looking forward to catching up on some reading — my digital to-read list is overflowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outsource Your Googling</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-11-jelly.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-11-jelly.html</guid>
      <description>Biz Stone, on the &amp;ldquo;un-pivot&amp;rdquo; relaunch of Jelly, his Q&amp;amp;A social network:
 Back in the day, folks would turn to friends with questions. Then came the web and search engines. These days most of us go straight to a search engine. Increasingly, people are asking on social media (which can sometimes be awkward). We think there is another way to get high quality answers without sifting through an ocean of “results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcome Mediocrity, Not Fear</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-30-newport-overcome-mediocrity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-30-newport-overcome-mediocrity.html</guid>
      <description>Cal Newport writing for his blog, Study Hacks:
 The courage culture paints a tempting picture of how people end up with remarkable lives. It tells a story where you&amp;rsquo;re the main character, fighting evil forces, and ultimately triumphing after a brief but intense battle.
  The reality is decidedly less exciting. Remarkable careers require that you become remarkably good. This takes time. But not necessarily a string of defiant rejections of some mysterious status quo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCWorld&#39;s review of Firewatch: 3/5</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-firewatch-reviews.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-firewatch-reviews.html</guid>
      <description>Last one for the night. Hayden Dingman, covering the game for PCWorld:
 Firewatch is beautiful. Firewatch is intriguing. But ultimately I don&amp;rsquo;t think Firewatch is very good. At its best, this is a quiet game about two characters struggling with real-life insecurities. But when that&amp;rsquo;s sidelined to make room for a main plot, Firewatch suffers. It&amp;rsquo;s a game perfect for trailers, a game full of excellent dialogue and breathtaking moments and stunning vistas that ultimately amounts to nothing much at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pebble Watch</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-01-pebble.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-01-pebble.html</guid>
      <description>Fun, clever, and cheery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pleasant Font Pairings</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-06-google-fonts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-06-google-fonts.html</guid>
      <description>I have been working with lots of web typography lately. However, although there is no shortage of web fonts available, I sometimes find it difficult identify nice font pairs.
Thankfully, the likes of Femmebot, Typekit, and Daniel Eden have helped us all, by doing a lot of legwork for us:
 Google Type Pairings by Femmebot Selecting Typefaces for Body Text by Typekit Just My Type by Daniel Eden  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasting Diaries</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-02-06-podcasting-pt-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-02-06-podcasting-pt-1.html</guid>
      <description>One of my goals for this semester is to start a small podcast. I have always loved public speaking, and I truly enjoy finding the stories of other people. Hopefully this will give me the chance to do just that.
After buying an awesome microphone [referral link], I spent the first few days just playing with various audio settings and was able to get a feel for how the microphone handles different environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasting Diaries 2</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-02-20-podcasting-pt-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-02-20-podcasting-pt-2.html</guid>
      <description>Now that The Log is officially up and running, I wanted to add another post to [my series]({% post_url 2014-02-06-podcasting-pt-1 %}) on things I have learned behind the mic.
The audience I am not the best show host quite yet. Although not yet published, I have recorded a couple of 30+ minute interviews with a variety of guests from around campus. While interviewing them, I quickly realized the importance of having a good set of questions or list of topics to help keep a common narrative throughout the show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polygon&#39;s review of Firewatch: 8.5/10</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-polygon-firewatch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-polygon-firewatch.html</guid>
      <description>Colin Campbell, reporting for Polygon:
 Delilah and Henry represent an emerging trend in games, of paired characters who are individually and collectively simpatico but who struggle with their own anxieties and with one another&amp;rsquo;s perceived shortcomings. Their relationship has form and shape, though it shimmers and shifts as the story progresses.
  These two characters are written with a conviction and authenticity rarely seen in video games. Neither of them is idealized, not even for a second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Advice for Traveling</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-08-rands-travel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-08-rands-travel.html</guid>
      <description>Great stuff by Michael Lopp on being efficient and smart when traveling. As I get closer to my honeymoon, we&amp;rsquo;re going out of country, I&amp;rsquo;ve been eating these types of articles up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare today</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-02-06-prepare-today.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-02-06-prepare-today.html</guid>
      <description>Walking back to the dorm in the cool air tonight, I came up with a neat way of thinking about work ethic and effort:
 Prepare today so you can do tomorrow what you couldn&amp;rsquo;t do yesterday.
 Sounds like a quote straight out of a self-help book, but there&amp;rsquo;s some real inspiration in there. Work hard to become a better, more healthy and loving person every day. Look in the mirror each night and ask yourself if you&amp;rsquo;ve made the world a little better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation: Mobile Web and Applications</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-02-17-mobile-presentation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-02-17-mobile-presentation.html</guid>
      <description>Update: The Alliance Review has posted the online version of the article that covered my presentation.
Whew, last week was packed for me. If you noticed the irregular publishing schedule, I apologize. Let me show you what took up most of my time.
About three months ago, I was asked by my university&amp;rsquo;s Office of Marketing to create a presentation about mobile applications. The audience would be a mix of business- and marketing-focused professionals, and my job was to both educate and advise as to the current state of mobile applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read Different</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-07-14-cbd-read-different.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-07-14-cbd-read-different.html</guid>
      <description>By guest editor, Christopher B. Durr.
 Do you want to be a better scientist? Study architecture, cooking, economics, mechanics. Go outside your field and ask questions.
 That&amp;rsquo;s some of the best advice I have ever been given. Too often we view the same sites on the Internet over and over again ad nauseam. Facebook, news, e-mail, rinse and repeat. The news is great for information but short on inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Cognitive Friction</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-02-blanc-little-things.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-02-blanc-little-things.html</guid>
      <description>Shawn Blanc:
 Computers are great at doing the boring, automated stuff we don’t like to do. So why not automate common tasks (like performing backups of your computer), pre-make decisions for your computer to carry out on your behalf (such as auto-filing certain email newsletters), and generally just find ways to make yourself more efficient?
  I think the biggest reason we don’t do these things is because we don’t care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reeder 2 for Mac Beta</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-04-11-reeder-2-beta.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-04-11-reeder-2-beta.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long-time fan of Silvio Rizzi&amp;rsquo;s Reeder 2 for iOS. Reeder is an excellent RSS client, and it remains my preferred way to consume news feeds on the go.
Earlier today, Rizzi announced a public beta of Reeder 2 for Mac. Anyone who wants to try the software before it is, presumably, sold on the Mac App Store can check it out here.
I&amp;rsquo;m pretty picky about the software I use to read news feeds with, particularly since I can go through hundreds of articles a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporter for iPhone</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-20-feltron-reporter-signup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-20-feltron-reporter-signup.html</guid>
      <description>Nicholas Feltron, the guy behind those incredibly-detailed self analysis reports, is getting ready to release Reporter for iPhone, a data-collecting tool that helps you track the quantifiable data in your life. From the pre-launch page:
 Reporter is a new application for tracking the things you care about. With a few randomly timed surveys each day, Reporter can illuminate aspects of your life that might be otherwise unmeasurable.
 Sign me up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporter for iPhone Released</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-06-reporter-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-06-reporter-released.html</guid>
      <description>Earlier this morning, Reporter for iPhone was officially released on the App Store. Reporter, the brainchild of data-analyst Nicholas Feltron, randomly presents you with lightweight surveys throughout the day, and then compiles that data into fascinating personal reports. At just $3.99 cheap, this will be one of the first apps I buy when I am off my [digital media hiatus]({% post_url 2014-01-15-things-i-could-have-bought %}).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Publications at Facebook</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-10-research-publications-at-facebook.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-10-research-publications-at-facebook.html</guid>
      <description>Facebook:
 Giving people the power to share and connect requires constant innovation. At Facebook, we solve technical problems no one else has seen because no one else has built a social network of this size.
    Working at the intersection of research and engineering to make the world more open and connected is one of the best things about being at Facebook right now.
 They&amp;rsquo;ve got some really interesting research papers compiled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rovio to Lose Some of Its Flock</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-02-rovio-job-cuts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-02-rovio-job-cuts.html</guid>
      <description>Sad news from Re/code, reporting on a story by Reuters:
 Finnish mobile games maker Rovio, owner of the Angry Birds brand, plans to cut up to 130 jobs in Finland, or 16 percent of its workforce, saying growth has not been as strong as expected and it needs a simpler structure.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samsung&#39;s Golden Galaxy S4</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-25-samsungs-fake-gold.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-25-samsungs-fake-gold.html</guid>
      <description>The Verge:
 Two weeks after Apple&amp;rsquo;s September 10th reveal of a champagne-colored iPhone, Samsung is launching its own golden phone in the shape of a new Gold Edition Galaxy S4.
 You could argue the old adage that &amp;ldquo;good artist copy, great artist steal.&amp;rdquo; But extraordinary artists steal great features, refine them, and then implement a better version. Samsung thinks copying features is enough, continuously duplicating other competitors without adding any real value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satya Nadella, Microsoft CEO</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-04-satya-nadella.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-04-satya-nadella.html</guid>
      <description>This evening, Microsoft announced that Satya Nadella, previously the Executive Vice President of Cloud and Enterprise, will be appointed to the position of CEO. Nadella becomes only the third CEO in the company&amp;rsquo;s history. From the official press page:
 &amp;ldquo;During this time of transformation, there is no better person to lead Microsoft than Satya Nadella,&amp;rdquo; said Bill Gates, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Founder and Member of the Board of Directors. &amp;ldquo;Satya is a proven leader with hard-core engineering skills, business vision and the ability to bring people together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch-Off Media</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-31-bowler-the-lottery.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-31-bowler-the-lottery.html</guid>
      <description>Chris Bowler, with some thoughtful reflection on the effects of getting everything in real time:
 But the real problem here is not the technology itself, but our perception of value. We&amp;rsquo;ve elevated the mundane to the top of our priority list and allowed the possibility of news from someone else to take precedence over our own work. That scares me.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search and destroy</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-09-09-search-and-destroy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-09-09-search-and-destroy.html</guid>
      <description>One of the hardest parts of keeping on top of your schedule at college is actually knowing what you have to do. Most of us get the work done, but sometimes I find myself wanting to avoid having to see what I need to do for a project. What little motivation I have is further squandered when I have to go out of my way to check on assignments; whether they&amp;rsquo;re online, or the teacher sends them out after class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serif Fours Look a Lot Like Nines</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-15-serif-fours-look-like-nines.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-15-serif-fours-look-like-nines.html</guid>
      <description>Fascinating little anecdote about how The New York Times&amp;rsquo; issue number was off by 500 for more than a century. Rebecca J. Rosen for The Atlantic:
 It&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to imagine the scene: A worker, late at night, setting the paper&amp;rsquo;s front-page type. He takes out the type from the preceding day&amp;rsquo;s paper. He looks at the issue number—14,499—and adds one. He gets 15,000.
  Perhaps he misread the number, and thought he saw 14,999 in its place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seth Godin on Writing</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-13-godin-writing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-13-godin-writing.html</guid>
      <description>Seth Godin:
 Our culture celebrates athletes that shape their bodies, and chieftains who build organizations. Lesser known, but more available, is the ability to work on our words until they succeed in transmitting our ideas and causing action.
  Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: you may not have the resources or the physique or the connections that people who do other sorts of work have. But you do have precisely the same keyboard as everyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shutting Down Facebook Paper</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-30-paper-doll.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-30-paper-doll.html</guid>
      <description>A year ago, Facebook announced a new News Feed that was completely redesigned to focus on content–it had large photos, big user icons, better integration with Facebook messenger, and it brought Facebook’s website into closer alignment with its mobile apps. It was beautiful. During the few months I was able to use the new design, my Facebook experience was significantly better. Here’s what it looked like:
 That&amp;rsquo;s Dustin Curtis, back in 2014, in a post titled &amp;ldquo;Whatever goes up, that&amp;rsquo;s what we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sidebar design</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-08-17-sidebar-design.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-08-17-sidebar-design.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m designing a sidebar for a web application, which has a typical header-sidebar-content layout. The header holds the main navigation, the content area has content, but the sidebar has a lot more:
 Two primary action buttons (think &amp;ldquo;create x&amp;rdquo; type). Two collapsible lists of content (you click the header to collapse the list). Two lists that are not collapsible.  We&amp;rsquo;ve put a lot in that sidebar, arguably too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skim PDF Reader for Mac</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-30-skim-pdf-reader.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-30-skim-pdf-reader.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the middle of reading through 30 research-heavy PDFs and needed a way to extract the text I highlighted while reading. A little bit of searching later and I found Skim. It does exactly what I wanted and has made my life much easier. If you do any sort of research and deal with lots of PDFs, go get Skim right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skype Makes Group Video Calling Free</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-28-skype-group-video.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-28-skype-group-video.html</guid>
      <description>Phillip Snalune, writing on the Skype company blog:
 For the last few years, we’ve offered group video calling to Premium users on Windows desktop and Mac and more recently Xbox One. Today, we’re excited to announce that we’re making group video calling free – for all users on these platforms. And, in the future, we’ll be enabling group video calling for all our users across more platforms – at no cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep and Winding Down</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-10-sleep.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-10-sleep.html</guid>
      <description>Tony Schwartz, writing for the Harvard Business Review:
 There is no single behavioral change we’ve seen in our work with thousands of executives that more quickly and powerfully influences mood, focus, and productivity than a full night’s sleep.
 Schwartz&amp;rsquo;s story revolves around an experimentation with Kevin Crain, a Managing Director at Bank of America, and his sleep schedule. Schwartz also later goes on to cite a study at the University of Warwick, which linked a lack of sleep (less than 6 hours a night) to a 48% increase in the likelihood of developing or dying from heart disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Fast Slow by Studio Neat</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-29-studio-neat-slow-fast-slow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-29-studio-neat-slow-fast-slow.html</guid>
      <description>One of the great features of the iPhone 5S&amp;rsquo; camera is the ability to take 120 fps (frames per second) video and then play it back in slow motion. Unfortunately, that feature is exclusive to the iPhone 5S.
Thankfully, the folks at Studio Neat have released an app called Slow Fast Slow which brings slo-mo video capabilities to the iPhone 5/5C/5S and iPod Touch (5th generation). The UI looks fantastic and much more usable than Apple&amp;rsquo;s own interface in Camera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Need a Typeface</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-24-so-you-need-a-typeface.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-24-so-you-need-a-typeface.html</guid>
      <description>Using Julian Hansen&amp;rsquo;s famous typeface-related poster as a starting point, Ian Li built an interactive version that retains the same charm as the original.
I like Li&amp;rsquo;s version (it&amp;rsquo;s certainly easier to navigate), but Hansen&amp;rsquo;s is great because I can work my way backwards through the logic tree, starting with a typeface instead of its eventual application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving iOS Battery Drain</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-09-ios-battery-drain.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-09-ios-battery-drain.html</guid>
      <description>Scotty Loveless, a former Apple Store Genius, has compiled a thorough list of things you can do to test, and increase, the battery life of your iOS devices. This part gave me a good chuckle:
 What most people tell you is that closing your apps will save your battery life because it keeps the apps from running in the background.
  Wrong.
 Nearly everyone I observe seems to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some More Details on Touch ID&#39;s Security</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-26-more-details-on-touch-id.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-26-more-details-on-touch-id.html</guid>
      <description>For the typical consumer, Apple has not gone too far in explaining the details behind Touch ID&amp;rsquo;s security. We know that your fingerprint data never leaves the Secure Enclave (a small, physical chip embedded on the processor), and that applications are restricted from ever asking for that data. However, for those of us who want to know more, particularly businesses, Apple has updated the security document that accompanies their iPhone in Business website to include a plethora of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some News from this Week</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-07-good-news.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-07-good-news.html</guid>
      <description>This past week, my school has been on spring break. I&amp;rsquo;ve been catching up on the news whenever I get a chance, but haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to do much writing. Nonetheless, here are some of the more choice news stories you should check out, should you have missed them:
The XP-Factor Peter Bright, in a recent article for Wired, shares that Windows XP still has 29% of the total computer operating system share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some stats from KDHQ</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-24-an-update-on-kd.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-24-an-update-on-kd.html</guid>
      <description>The past few weeks at the KDHQ have been fun, and I want to share some stats and updates.
Note: all statistics derived from data collected between Sep. 2 and Oct. 24 of 2013.
Traffic  Highest traffic in a single day: 50 unique visitors Total pageviews: 1,816  Posts statistics  11 articles written 17 items linked to 7,299 words written  Operating System Breakdowns  iOS: 36.5% Windows: 35.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spoken word &#34;Love&#34;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-01-26-spoken-word-love.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-01-26-spoken-word-love.html</guid>
      <description>Had an interesting reflection experience.
I felt really inspired after watching some of Jeff Bethke&amp;rsquo;s videos. I took this inspiration, along with my Macbook, and went to the BnB cafe. I grabbed a drink, sat down and took some quiet time to clear my mind. What I ended up doing was writing my first “spoken word” poetry piece. I really liked how it turned out, so I got creative and even made a video for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Square Cash</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-16-square-cash.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-16-square-cash.html</guid>
      <description>Really fascinating new service from Square that lets you transfer money to anyone&amp;rsquo;s debit card with a single email — no account required and zero fees. I can see college students getting tons of use out of this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscribe by Email</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-28-sub-by-email.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-28-sub-by-email.html</guid>
      <description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that you can subscribe to this site&amp;rsquo;s posts via email. Subscribe-by-email has been one of the most requested features I&amp;rsquo;ve received over the past few months, and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to finally be able to provide the service. If you head over to the Subscribe page, you can submit your email to get started. As of now, posts will be sent once a day, whenever there are new posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Svbtle and Medium</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-01-31-me-vs-we.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-01-31-me-vs-we.html</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago, Dustin Curtis opened up registration for his blogging platform, Svbtle:
 Svbtle is designed to highlight the things that matter; it&amp;rsquo;s an extremely simple platform for collecting and developing ideas, sharing them with the world, and reading them. That&amp;rsquo;s it. We&amp;rsquo;ve focused all of our energy into designing the simplest interface possible for accomplishing these goals. Svbtle is blogging with everything else stripped away.
 Svbtle now joins Medium as a new place to write online, with the each service encouraging narratives that are longer than 140 characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss Army</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-02-29-swiss-army.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-02-29-swiss-army.html</guid>
      <description>I love Swiss Army knives. When I was a kid, I had a red-handled one that had all the essential things a boy on a small farm needed. I used to spend hours whittling away at sticks, or tightening up the screws on my toys and bike. More than once, the tweezers were brought out to get a microscopic splinter out of my palm. I used the heck out of that thing and it always found a place in my pocket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync Google Fonts to Your Desktop</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-05-sync-google-fonts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-05-sync-google-fonts.html</guid>
      <description>Fonts.com has put together a pretty cool new service, dubbed SkyFonts, that lets you sync any of Google Fonts&amp;rsquo; 1,173 typefaces to your computer:
 We are proud to have teamed up with Google to offer desktop versions of their popular Google Fonts free of charge. Offered for use in print, these fonts are delivered using SkyFont’s patent-pending font delivery technology and can be used anywhere.
  Each time a font is updated — such as when new characters are added — SkyFonts will automatically update the font on your device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis: Apple Acquires Beats Music and Beats Electronics</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-29-apple-to-buy-beats.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-29-apple-to-buy-beats.html</guid>
      <description>Planning to close the deal later this year, Apple will pay $3 billion to acquire Beats Music and Beats Electronics. Beats co-founders Jimmy Iovine and Dr. Dre will also be joining Apple as employees.
Straight from the horse&amp;rsquo;s mouth, via Apple PR:
 “Music is such an important part of Apple’s DNA and always will be,” said Eddy Cue, Apple’s senior vice president of Internet Software and Services. “The addition of Beats will make our music lineup even better, from free streaming with iTunes Radio to a world-class subscription service in Beats, and of course buying music from the iTunes Store as customers have loved to do for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tapbots and iOS 7</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-17-tapbots-and-ios-7.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-17-tapbots-and-ios-7.html</guid>
      <description>When iOS 7 was announced, it instantly made most of the apps in the App Store look old and outdated; apps that had previously made heavy use of graphics and images looked out of place in contrast to iOS 7&amp;rsquo;s flatness.
One of my favorite app developer teams, Tapbots, was hit particularly hard by the iOS 7 announcement. Over the past several years, the Tapbots team, Mark Jardine (design) and Paul Haddad (code), had built a company by designing highly-customized user interfaces for their applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text files</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-06-22-text-files.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-06-22-text-files.html</guid>
      <description>Text files are one of those things that will never go away. They are organic to the computer world and are supported by every operating system. However, many people don&amp;rsquo;t take advantage of the awesome powers that text files hold. Here is my quick and simple guide to start implementing a little more text into your lifestyle.
Open up an editor One the Mac? Use TextEdit in plain text mode. On the PC?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TextEdit</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-12-14-textedit.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-12-14-textedit.html</guid>
      <description>Can we take a moment to thank the folks at Apple for TextEdit? I&amp;rsquo;m serious. There is no shortage of text editors for OS X, yet I find myself continually coming back to TextEdit. It&amp;rsquo;s fast, simple, open source [1], and every Mac has a copy preinstalled. Pick out a nice monospaced font, and I think you have a challenger for even the most minimalistic of writing interfaces.
Apple&amp;rsquo;s OS X apps tend get a lot of criticism, but after 10 years and tens of thousands of words, I have yet to have a major issue with TextEdit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving Break</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-26-thanksgiving-break.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-26-thanksgiving-break.html</guid>
      <description>My Thanksgiving break begins today after classes finish at 5 p.m. Given that the next few days will be filled with food, family, and traveling, KDHQ will be happily shutting down our web browsers until next week.
I hope each of you have a blessed and safe holiday, and I ask everyone to be careful while traveling as Winter Storm &amp;ldquo;Boreas&amp;rdquo; looks to drop plenty of snow and ice in the Eastern United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That&#39;ll Be $1,850</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-21-simmons-network-solutions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-21-simmons-network-solutions.html</guid>
      <description>Brent Simmons, a Mac and iOS developer, recently received an email from his domain registrar, Network Solutions, informing him that his account had been automatically enrolled into a new security program, WebLock, and that his credit card would &amp;ldquo;be billed $1,850 for the first year of service.&amp;rdquo;
Read that again. A company opted-in a customer to a program that costs over $1,500 a year, and they only informed him after the deed was done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2013 List of Worst Passwords</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-20-passwords.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-20-passwords.html</guid>
      <description>SplashData, the company behind an annual &amp;ldquo;Worst Passwords&amp;rdquo; index, has released their 2013 report, listing the 25 most-used passwords on the internet.
Notable changes from last year: &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo; was usurped by &amp;ldquo;123456&amp;rdquo; for the top spot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adaptive Tab Bar</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-03-adaptive-tab-bar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-03-adaptive-tab-bar.html</guid>
      <description>Interesting user interface concept from the folks at Ramotion. The longer you use an application, the simpler its interface becomes.
I like the idea, but I really hope designers don&amp;rsquo;t go wild with this concept. Progressive reduction can be useful, even more efficient, for certain types of applications and certain types of users, but people tend to not do well with change — much less if it happens without their consent [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Mobile</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-05-om-whatsapp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-05-om-whatsapp.html</guid>
      <description>Om Malik, the founder of Gigaom, put together some truly awesome charts that help illustrate, and give context to, the meteoric rise of WhatsApp:
 These charts show that not only WhatsApp is different, but it is exceptional and did well to capture the moment (i.e., rise of the mobile broadband) near perfectly. They are also not just exceptional, they are a standout with highest rate of growth and getting to that point the fastest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Amazon Smartphone</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-15-amazon-smartphone.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-15-amazon-smartphone.html</guid>
      <description>Zach Epstein, writing for BGR (yup, [that BGR]({% post_url 2013-10-19-foolish-bgr %})):
 The main rear camera is thought to feature a resolution of 13 megapixels, and the phone also includes a standard front-facing camera for video chats as well as Amazon’s Mayday customer service feature.
  Beyond those two units, the device houses an additional four front-facing cameras that work with other sensors to facilitate the software’s 3D effects. One source tells us these four cameras, which are situated in each of the four corners on the face of the phone, are low-power infrared cameras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Billionaire&#39;s Typewriter</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-01-billionaires-typewriter.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-01-billionaires-typewriter.html</guid>
      <description>Matthew Butterick:
 But by the end, I re­al­ized I dis­agree deeply with Medium about the ethics of de­sign. And by ethics, I mean some­thing sim­ple: though Medium and I are both mak­ing tools for writ­ers, what I want for writ­ers and what Medium wants couldn’t be more dif­fer­ent.
 And later:
 In truth, Medium’s main prod­uct is not a pub­lish­ing plat­form, but the pro­mo­tion of a pub­lish­ing plat­form. This pro­mo­tion brings read­ers and writ­ers onto the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bullet Journal Note-Taking System</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-20-bullet-journal.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-20-bullet-journal.html</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you love taking notes by hand. The Bullet Journal, developed by art director and designer Ryder Carroll, is a note-taking system that focuses on helping quickly collect and find all your daily todos and notes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for the past few months and have found it to be a very personal, elegant way of organizing my daily life.
The primary place I&amp;rsquo;ve started using it is with my school notebooks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cramped</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-07-the-cramped.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-07-the-cramped.html</guid>
      <description>Patrick Rhone, one of my favorite online writers, just started a new site called The Cramped:
 If you are the sort of person who appreciates nice paper, a decent pen, a well-crafted notebook, a solid pencil, writing and receiving handwritten correspondence, beautiful handwriting, or the clicky-clack of a dependable typewriter, you have come to the right place. The Cramped is a site dedicated to the pleasures of writing with analog tools (the name is purposefully ironic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GORUCK GR0</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-09-goruck-gr0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-09-goruck-gr0.html</guid>
      <description>Sweet new bag from the folks at GORUCK:
 GR0 is exactly proportionate to GR1, only 5 liters smaller. Fitwise, if you&amp;rsquo;re under 6&amp;rsquo; tall, GR0. Over 6&amp;rsquo; tall, GR1. GR0 has all the same features as GR1, including 3 rows of MOLLE webbing and compatibility with the GR1 Field Pocket.
 Same great build, smaller package. However, based on [my own experience with the GR1]({% post_url 2013-09-09-my-gear %}) (I&amp;rsquo;m 5-8), I&amp;rsquo;d recommend the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grinch</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-12-18-the-grinch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-12-18-the-grinch.html</guid>
      <description>How the Grinch Stole Christmas is one of my favorite movies to watch when December roles around. In fact, it was one of the first movies I remember going to see in theaters as a family. I recall we all went to a matinée showing before heading to a family Christmas party. The Grinch also got my dad to laugh out loud, multiple times, something that few movies can claim to have done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Guardian&#39;s Review of Firewatch: 4/5</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-guardian-firewatch-review.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-02-08-guardian-firewatch-review.html</guid>
      <description>Notes on spoilers: Although my comments and pull-quotes below are spolier-free, the Guardian&amp;rsquo;s review reveals a number of plot details for Firewatch. If you want to go into the game completely fresh, save the full piece for later this week.
The Guardian&amp;rsquo;s Nathan Ditum, in his review of Firewatch:
 The writing is not just believable, it is likeable and funny. Henry and Delilah’s exchanges are full of the familiar tug and tarry of people getting to know each other, of playing and of flirting, and of reaching out to feel less alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Beauty of Airport Runways</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-24-airport-beauty.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-24-airport-beauty.html</guid>
      <description>Fascinating article on the work of Lauren O’Neil, a Brooklyn-based designer who uses Google Earth to capture images of airport runway layouts. Joseph Flaherty, writing for WIRED:
 O&amp;rsquo;Neil turns those strictures [airport runways] into art, with the help of Google Earth. The Brooklyn-based designer has made a meticulous study of airport runways and logged the results on a Tumblr called Holding Pattern. These views reveal beautiful compositions at airports that are nothing special at ground level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hollywood Reporter&#39;s Hour with Ridley Scott, Tarantino, and More</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-06-filmaking-roundtable.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-06-filmaking-roundtable.html</guid>
      <description>A roundtable on filmmaking, with the filmmakers. Scott is incredibly measured, Tarantino is quintessentially eccentric, and I enjoyed whenever the discussion turned to them talking about their own writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ikea bookbook</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-22-ikea-bookbook.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-22-ikea-bookbook.html</guid>
      <description>Ikea, six days before Apple&amp;rsquo;s September event, released a clever, short video, introducing the Ikea bookbook. From the video description:
 At only 8mm thin, and weighing in at less than 400g, the 2015 IKEA Catalogue comes pre-installed with thousands of home furnishing ideas.
 Fun, and in good taste.
To be fair, the iPhone 6 and 6+ are thinner than the bookbook; however, not even Apple&amp;rsquo;s best can beat that bookbook&amp;rsquo;s battery life and built-in security features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Journaling</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-10-30-on-the-importance-of-journaling.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-10-30-on-the-importance-of-journaling.html</guid>
      <description>Richard Holmes always gave us ice cream. Whenever my siblings and I would walk down the road to say hello, the first thing he&amp;rsquo;d do would be to tell us there&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;ice cream in the back.&amp;rdquo; Although he was just a neighbor who lived down the road, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure he never actually ate any of the ice cream he bought for us. It was just something he did for our benefit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kinsa Thermometer</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-09-the-kinsa-thermometer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-09-the-kinsa-thermometer.html</guid>
      <description>These past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been sick with a cold. When ill, one of the things I always do is keep a diligent hand-written journal of any medication I took and all the corresponding times. I&amp;rsquo;ve often thought about building a simple app to manage this for me, but Inder Singh, the executive vice president of the Clinton Health Access from 2008 to 2011, looks to be taking this idea one step further with, what he calls, the &amp;ldquo;World&amp;rsquo;s Smartest Thermometer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Legend of &#34;Open&#34;</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-25-zelda-open-world.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-06-25-zelda-open-world.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I prefer not to use the generally used term &amp;lsquo;open world&amp;rsquo; when developing software, but we used this term [at E3] in order to make it easier for consumers to understand. This term means that there is a large world in which players can do numerous things daily.&amp;rdquo;
 That&amp;rsquo;s Shigeru Miyamoto at Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s latest shareholders meeting, reported on by Lucy O&amp;rsquo;Brien, for IGN.
 With this said, Miyamoto does not hesitate to call Zelda&amp;rsquo;s new world &amp;ldquo;vast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Log Podcast</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-19-introducing-the-log.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-19-introducing-the-log.html</guid>
      <description>Last night, I flipped the switch on my latest project, The Log Podcast [1].
I really can&amp;rsquo;t tell you just how excited I am to launch this. Not only has daily readership of the site reached a point where I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable to start branching out into different mediums, but I now have a way of reaching my readers through a medium I have a great passion for: public speaking. For the past few months I had been working out the logistics of getting a podcast up and running, and finally being able to get something out there feels great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mac Keeps Going</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-24-mac-keeps-going.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-24-mac-keeps-going.html</guid>
      <description>After returning from Christmas break, I noticed a lot of students carrying around Microsoft Surface tablets. I see these devices in meetings, in class, and anywhere there is a surface (ha) to put them. What I have yet to see, however, is anyone using the Surface exclusively as a tablet.
I have had the chance to use these devices, and they are good laptops if you like Windows, but they are not good tablets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New iPads</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-11-14-brief-thoughts-on-the-new-ipads.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-11-14-brief-thoughts-on-the-new-ipads.html</guid>
      <description>Apple&amp;rsquo;s got two new iPads out, and I finally got to play with both of them this past weekend at my local Apple Store. Here are my thoughts after about 10 minutes with each device.
Note: For this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be shortening both iPad names to just &amp;ldquo;Air&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Retina Mini.&amp;quot;
Lighter than Air The first thing you notice about the Air is what&amp;rsquo;s not there. At just 1 pound (1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Underdog</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-27-wiskus-ms.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-27-wiskus-ms.html</guid>
      <description>Dave Wiskus, an iOS developer, writing about his experience at the 2014 Microsoft Build conference:
 When I say that walking around the floor of Microsoft’s Build conference was weird, I don’t mean that from the perspective of an iOS designer who crossed enemy lines. I felt more like some kind of war-torn refugee, returning to find that home had been rebuilt into a palace. For all the years I spent trying to escape from this company, the place seemed friendly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Newsprint&#39;s Review of Vesper</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-09-ginter.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-09-ginter.html</guid>
      <description>I had been meaning to point out Joshua Ginter&amp;rsquo;s review format for a while now. Weaving real-world images with screenshots of Vesper (screenshots, which are framed in simple, color-aware containers), Mr. Ginter&amp;rsquo;s review style is one of my favorites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next America</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-12-the-next-america.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-12-the-next-america.html</guid>
      <description>Paul Taylor, writing for the Pew Research Center:
 At a time when young and old don’t look alike, think alike or vote alike, how will America modernize its entitlement programs so they&amp;rsquo;re in sync with its new demographics? How can we keep faith with the old without bankrupting the young and starving the future? It will be difficult.
 This is an excellent example of data analysis and narrative, packaged in a beautiful, responsive web design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nifty MiniDrive</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-18-nifty-minidrive.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-18-nifty-minidrive.html</guid>
      <description>The Nifty MiniDrive is a new, 64GB SD card available for the Macbook. Although there is no shortage of SD cards available on Amazon [affiliate link], the MiniDrive is shorter than a standard SD card, which means that, once inserted, it will remain flush against the side, instead of protruding out.
Nifty is currently selling the 64GB card (in black or red) for $39.99 and will throw in a free 2GB card with every order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NYT Diff</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-26-nyt-diff.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-26-nyt-diff.html</guid>
      <description>The Diff (presumably named for the programming notion of viewing changes in code) is a fascinating little device from the Times that monitors their online headlines and prints out a visual representation of any changes that occur. Noah Feehan, writing for the NYT Labs blog:
 Diff is a small device that monitors the internal events stream of The New York Times and prints out a summary each time an active headline is changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Past 80 Years of World Cup Ticket Design</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-06-19-wc-tickets.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-06-19-wc-tickets.html</guid>
      <description>Both the 1958 (Sweeden) and 1966 (England) designs are fantastic. If I had to pick one, it would be Sweeden&amp;rsquo;s for the great serif numerals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Privacy We Give Away</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-29-the-privacy-we-give-away.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-29-the-privacy-we-give-away.html</guid>
      <description>Naoki Hiroshima recently went through a horrifying experience of losing his Twitter handle, @N. Through social engineering, a hacker was able to access Hiroshima&amp;rsquo;s GoDaddy account, email, and Facebook profile, and then used them to exhort Hiroshima for access to the Twitter username. The whole story is chilling, and many of us are far more susceptible to this sort of event than we think. Hiroshima:
 I tried to log in to my GoDaddy account, but it didn’t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Serial Podcast</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-07-serial-podcast.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-07-serial-podcast.html</guid>
      <description>A new podcast, from the folks at This American Life:
 Their relationship began like a storybook high-school romance: a prom date, love notes, sneaking off to be alone. But unlike other kids at school, they had to keep their dating secret, because their parents disapproved. Both of them, but especially Adnan, were under special pressure at home, and the stress of that spilled over into their relationship. Eventually Hae broke up with Adnan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unpublished</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-22-the-unpublished.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-22-the-unpublished.html</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, as a writer, a nagging thought or idea will torment you relentlessly until you slay it with a hot iron sword of words and punctuation. However, not all battles lead to a publishable work; sometimes the ideas were so battered by the battle, the only consolation they can give is the peace of mind that you emerged victorious.
Here&amp;rsquo;s to the unpublished posts of writers everywhere. To that idea that needed written out, but then offered up little in the way of adding anything meaningful to existing conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Week in Review</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-16-week-in-review.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-12-16-week-in-review.html</guid>
      <description>Exams are now over and so [is my hiatus]({% post_url 2013-12-06-exams %}). Although I had limited time to read anything other than my notes from class, I saved several articles that I found particularly interesting and worth mentioning:
 CNN put out a great photo set of &amp;ldquo;the worlds most exquisite libraries,&amp;rdquo; and the images are incredible. There are many places I&amp;rsquo;d love to visit in this world, but these libraries just jumped to the top of my list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Press Photo Awards</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-15-world-press-photos.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-15-world-press-photos.html</guid>
      <description>5,754 photographers, from 132 nationalities, took over 98,000 photographs for the 57th World Press Photo Contest.
Striking, raw looks at humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wrong Dictionary</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-11-somers-dictionary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-11-somers-dictionary.html</guid>
      <description>James Somers:
 [In a dictionary], words are boiled to their essence. But that essence is dry, functional, almost bureaucratically sapped of color or pop, like high modernist architecture. Which trains you to think of the dictionary as a utility, not a quarry of good things, not a place you’d go to explore and savor.
  Worse, the words themselves take on the character of their definitions: they are likewise reduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Could Have Bought</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-15-things-i-could-have-bought.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-15-things-i-could-have-bought.html</guid>
      <description>As I sat here debating which RSS syncing service to invest in, a familiar tug on my conscience appeared. Do I really need this service? What problem does it solve? Could $18 be better spent?
For the past few weeks, God&amp;rsquo;s been asking me these types of questions, and I&amp;rsquo;ve done my best to avoid listening. But tonight, inspired in part by my soon-to-be sister-in-law&amp;rsquo;s yearlong hiatus from buying anything nonessential, I finally stopped avoiding His queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three part relationship</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-07-29-three-part-relationship.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-07-29-three-part-relationship.html</guid>
      <description>Cue scene. Two people, attracted to the other, enter into a form of friendship that seems to extend beyond the capacity of a friendship. Slowly, as time goes by, those two people begin to build a new sort of relationship; one that is the curation of the experiences they&amp;rsquo;ve shared together as a couple. It&amp;rsquo;s an awesome thing to watch others go through, and to have the opportunity to experience yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threes!</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-10-threes-for-ios.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-02-10-threes-for-ios.html</guid>
      <description>New math-based iOS game from the creators of Ridiculous Fishing, Greg Wohlwend and Asher Vollmer. Blending math and strategy, Threes! looks incredibly addicting. If you are more of a visual person, I found the trailer does a great job of explaining the gameplay.
Andrew Webster, writing for The Verge:
 Your time in Threes is really only spent doing one thing — adding numbers together to make bigger ones. Yet it remains constantly engaging despite its seemingly simplistic nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tim Van Damme on The Great Discontent</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-28-maxvoltar-tgd.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-28-maxvoltar-tgd.html</guid>
      <description>Over on The Great Discontent (TGD), Tina Essmaker just published her interview with Dropbox designer, Tim Van Damme.
I have followed the work of Van Damme, maxvoltar, for the past five years. I initially heard about Van Damme when I was looking into the faces behind the, now defunct, Gowalla iOS app. Van Damme, originally from Belgium, was one of their designers. After Gowalla was acquired by Facebook, I then followed Van Damme&amp;rsquo;s career as he moved to Instagram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Mobile Design</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-14-lukew-tips.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-04-14-lukew-tips.html</guid>
      <description>A collection of usability and user experience tweets from design veteran, Luke Wroblewski. If you design for mobile screens, check these out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tobias Frere-Jones is Suing Jonathan Hoefler</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-17-frere-jones-sues-hoefler.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-17-frere-jones-sues-hoefler.html</guid>
      <description>This news broke yesterday afternoon, but I wanted to let it simmer for a while before commenting. Given that Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones (H&amp;amp;FJ) is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s best type foundries (their fonts in use by Nike, the Obama campaign, and numerous other national agencies), I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether the headlines about one of the founders suing the other were simply sensational and overreacting to something much smaller.
I was wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweetbot 3 FAQ</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-27-tweetbot-faq.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-27-tweetbot-faq.html</guid>
      <description>Tapbots answers some questions, and hint at some upcoming features, for Tweetbot 3. Noteworthy tidbits:
 Text size is tied to iOS 7&amp;rsquo;s dynamic font size in Settings.app &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; Text Size. A night theme is coming(!). Tweetbot 2 will eventually return to the App Store, but you can re-download it if you&amp;rsquo;ve previously purchased a copy in App Store.app &amp;gt; Purchased. Tweetbot for OS X will be getting an update to bring Mavericks compatibility in the coming weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweetbot 3.0</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-27-tweetbot-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-10-27-tweetbot-3.html</guid>
      <description>The best Twitter client for iOS got a huge update this week. Tapbots completely redesigned Tweetbot to match the aesthetic of iOS 7, and it&amp;rsquo;s currently on sale for $2.99 in the App Store.
John Gruber:
 Tapbots painted themselves into a corner with their previous look and feel — they were the ziggyest thing going, but with iOS 7, Apple zagged. They&amp;rsquo;ve figured out a way to drop the zig but still maintain a very distinctive character in the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two thoughts and an idea for Work in Progress</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-09-16-thoughts-on-work-in-progress.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2015-09-16-thoughts-on-work-in-progress.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching a lot of Work in Progress (WIP), an informal video series about product design by Jason Fried, of Basecamp, and Nate Kontny, of Highrise. It&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of fun, and I encourage you to check out their YouTube channel.
In Show #16, both Jason and Nate started chatting about ways they could increase viewership. Ideas ranged from email blasts to putting the audio version of WIP on iTunes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two types of photographs</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-09-02-two-types-of-photographs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2011-09-02-two-types-of-photographs.html</guid>
      <description>There are typically two types of photographs. The ones where the subjects are staged and ready for the shot, and the other where they are caught in the middle of another activity. I love the latter.
Photographs, to me, represent a snapshot of our personalities. I have nothing against staged photographs, where would family portraits be without them, but I prefer to see photos of people doing things. Riding a bike, about to kiss, or caught mid laughing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two years</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-03-23-two-years.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-03-23-two-years.html</guid>
      <description>[One year ago]({% post_url 2012-03-23-one-year %}) I wrote about how blessed I felt that God put Emily in my life. One year later we know each other better than ever, and I wake up each morning excited when I think about what the future holds for us.
my favorite jogging buddyTimothy Keller once wrote that there is no feeling like &amp;ldquo;the profound satisfaction of being known and loved.&amp;rdquo; Over the past two years, Emily has shown me that she not only loves me, but all my quirks as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-Thousand Forty-Eight</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-10-2048-game.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-10-2048-game.html</guid>
      <description>2048 is a new free, web-based game that mimics the gameplay of the popular iOS game, Threes! The same tile-mashing rules apply — only tiles of the same value can be combined — but 2048 changes the way that tiles move. Specifically, moving tiles in any direction slides those tiles until they hit a wall or another tile. You lose the fine-grained control over each move that I love in Threes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typekit</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-07-typekit.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2012-05-07-typekit.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Typekit to serve up the fonts you see here and have been very pleased. Normally, when you want to use a custom font on your website, you need to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s a font that your visitors have installed on their machines. If they don&amp;rsquo;t have that particular font, their browser will revert to using a default, and ugly, backup.
However, Typekit lets you use any font you want, even if the visitor doesn&amp;rsquo;t have it installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uber Taken to Court Over Death of Child</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-27-uber.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-27-uber.html</guid>
      <description>Uber, the company that offers on-demand taxi rides via mobile app, is being taken to court over the death of 6-year-old Sofia Liu. Liu was hit and killed by one of Uber&amp;rsquo;s cars on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve by an Uber driver who was waiting for a fare.
Uber asserts that Uber drivers without fares are not Uber cars. The suit, filed by Chris Dolan, a San Francisco lawyer, directly challenges this effort by the company to detach itself from its own users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Tabs in the Mavericks Finder</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-05-tidbits-mavericks-tabs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-05-tidbits-mavericks-tabs.html</guid>
      <description>Great collection of tips. Also useful if you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten that the Finder can now create tabs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the right tools</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-09-03-the-right-tools.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-09-03-the-right-tools.html</guid>
      <description>The other day I was trying to open the battery cover on our new electronic-banking Monopoly game set. I was having a problem getting the cover off because it was screwed into the hard plastic casing that made up the banking device. Quickly looking around for a phillips screwdriver proved unsuccessful, so I did what any other man would do; improvised.
After trying to use both a butter knife and a slightly bent paper clip, I was still unable to open the battery door.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vesper Support Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-05-vesper-support-guidelines.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-11-05-vesper-support-guidelines.html</guid>
      <description>Over on the Q Branch blog, Dave Wiskus wrote about how he approaches support for Vesper:
 Contacting support is part of the experience of using Vesper, so how can we design this part of the experience with the same care and consideration we put into the software itself?
 Wiskus has some excellent guidelines listed, and for me — as a customer — seeing these types of posts reaffirm how [much I love this app]({% post_url 2013-07-13-vesper %}).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vesper Sync</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-27-vesper-sync.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-27-vesper-sync.html</guid>
      <description>John Gruber, writing over on the Vesper blog, announcing Vesper 2.0 with Vesper Syncing:
 There is no charge. No subscription. You just create an account using your email address as your identity and it works.
 Vesper remains my [note-taking app of choice]({% post_url 2013-07-13-vesper %}), and this is a great update. But what&amp;rsquo;s next for Vesper? To my joy, a Mac client; Gruber:
 We have several ideas for future Vesper clients, but we’ve decided which one we’re going to tackle next: Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video of the New Tesla D, Zero to 60 in 3.2</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-11-model-sd.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-10-11-model-sd.html</guid>
      <description>No shifting of gears, just pure acceleration. Listen to the audio in the video; it sounds like a rocket ship. A $120 thousand rocket ship, anyhow.
I would love to own an electric vehicle one day; I think they&amp;rsquo;re the future of transportation for this world. And once we increase efficiency, or drastically reduce the cost, of solar technology, then things get really interesting.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in electric vehicles, be sure to check out what the motorcycles are doing in this space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voice and Tone</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-21-mailchimp-voice-and-tone.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-21-mailchimp-voice-and-tone.html</guid>
      <description>The rhetorical style guide for the writers at digital-newsletter company, MailChimp:
 Before you write content for MailChimp, it’s important to think about our readers. Though our voice doesn’t change, our tone adapts to our users’ feelings.
 Even with short, one-sentence copy, it is critical to understand the context of your users&amp;rsquo; emotions and state of mind. More companies should have documents like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Know What You&#39;re Doing</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-30-we-know-what-youre-doing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-30-we-know-what-youre-doing.html</guid>
      <description>Callum Haywood has put together an online-privacy awareness site called We Know What You&amp;rsquo;re Doing. Pulling in public status updates from Facebook and Foursquare, the site groups each update into one of several categories, ranging from &amp;ldquo;who wants to get fired?&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;who&amp;rsquo;s got a new phone number?&amp;rdquo;
This site operates in similar vein to the, now defunct, PleaseRobMe.com. PleaseRobMe pulled in public check-in data from Foursquare, alluding to the notion that if someone is checking-in to a cafe, their home is unoccupied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Creating a Culture of Distraction</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-26-kraus-distraction.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2013-09-26-kraus-distraction.html</guid>
      <description>Joe Kraus, writing about the growing cultural acceptance of being &amp;ldquo;distracted,&amp;rdquo; and our concept of multi-tasking:
 It&amp;rsquo;s shown not only that we&amp;rsquo;re dumber when we do this [multi-task] (an average of 10 IQ points dumber — that&amp;rsquo;s the same as pulling an all-nighter.), but that we&amp;rsquo;re also 40% less efficient at whatever it is we&amp;rsquo;re doing.
 Twentysomethings: we really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be ignoring these trends. One of the most important contributing factors to being productive is the amount of uninterupted time you get each day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Inspector Turns 10</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-16-10-years-of-web-inspector.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-01-16-10-years-of-web-inspector.html</guid>
      <description>Safari&amp;rsquo;s Web Inspector turned every website into an interactive blueprint, and I spent hours exploring all the code that powered my favorite websites. Having access to that information was instrumental in me getting started with web design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s in a Single Drop of Seawater</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-07-seawater.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-07-seawater.html</guid>
      <description>I could spend hours looking at things through a microscope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Every Story Looks the Same</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-31-salmon-beautiful-stories.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-03-31-salmon-beautiful-stories.html</guid>
      <description>The trend towards big and beautiful online article design is becoming more common. This past year, the New York Times went through a large redesign, focusing on bigger type and giving every article a command of the page. Just this last month, Time.com did the same, rolling out a new, bigger layout — following the same large-article trend as the Times.
Although these new layouts bode well for readability, Felix Salmon, writing for Rueters, argues that the change in design removes important visual cues that determine whether an article is important or not:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitney</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-08-typography.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-08-typography.html</guid>
      <description>Avenir Next has long been my typeface of choice for kyledreger.com. However, Avenir Next only comes pre-installed on OS X machines, which means that I had to fallback to system fonts for my Windows readers.
As I was working on a typographical refresh of the entire site, I decided that it was time to choose a webfont that would appear the same to all readers, as the font family would be served with the webpage itself and agnostic to the operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wii Sports</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-01-03-wii-sports.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-01-03-wii-sports.html</guid>
      <description>My family owns a Wii. However, we only own one game - Wii Sports.
I love Wii Sports, it&amp;rsquo;s brilliant. Although it was primarily created as a way to show new Wii users the basics of the then-new interaction between the Wii remotes and gameplay, many of the games are incredibly addictive and well designed. In an area where Nintendo could have just included a tutorial, they chose to build something really awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words Matter</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-15-words-matter.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-01-15-words-matter.html</guid>
      <description>Subtitle: The FCC just stabbed the open internet in the heart.
Yesterday, a DC court ruled against the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), stating that internet service providers (ISPs like Time Warner Cable, Verizon, etc.) no longer have to be regulated under common carrier policies. Without going too deep into what is an incredibly confusing issue, often called &amp;ldquo;net neutrality&amp;rdquo; in the news, the term common carrier essentially labels a service — like phone lines — as dumb pipes; they can carry data back and forth between destinations, but the companies are not allowed to discriminating against what type of data is being transferred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World War Tech</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-07-tech-war.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2016-07-07-tech-war.html</guid>
      <description>Nick Bilton, for Vanity Fair:
 It doesn’t take a political scientist to see that the world is on edge. And technology, we often forget, undergirds this political reality. The Internet and innovation have made cultures around the globe collide with historically unprecedented force. With the exception of perhaps a handful of rogue states, like North Korea, we all now eat at the same McDonald’s, use the same iPhones and discuss the same hot-button topics on the same social networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writer Pro for Mac</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-12-19-writer-pro-for-mac.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2013-12-19-writer-pro-for-mac.html</guid>
      <description>If you had to categorize me with one word, it would be &amp;ldquo;writer.&amp;rdquo; As a student of computer science and rhetorical composition (fancy words for writing), I take the tools I use very seriously. The programmer in me wants efficiency and innovation, and the writer in me wants tools that facilitate accurate editing and my personal writing processes. For a while, it was just me and TextEdit, the default text-editor on the Mac, pounding away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing like a hacker</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-03-05-writing-like-a-hacker.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2012-03-05-writing-like-a-hacker.html</guid>
      <description>Abstract: From history to English, I write all my school papers like a hacker. Using text editors without support for spell checking or formatting, I create a frictionless creative flow which allows me get my ideas out faster.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing for a long time, even though I&amp;rsquo;m not the best at it. Nevertheless, ever since I was a little kid, I would sit down and write stories and journal away my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing simple code</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-12-03-writing-simple-code.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2011-12-03-writing-simple-code.html</guid>
      <description>With three different computer science classes this semester, I write a lot of code. However, being a minimalistic type of guy, I try to have my code require as little documentation as possible. I do this by writing my code so that it explains itself without the need for an army of comments.
Unfortunately, many of the coding tutorials online, and even sample code from my classes, end up looking like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WWDC 2014</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-06-02-wwdc-2014.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/ok/2014-06-02-wwdc-2014.html</guid>
      <description>After today&amp;rsquo;s WWDC keynote, I need a week or so to absorb everything I just saw. Apple always puts on a great presentation, but they were in rare form this morning. A lot of the praise has to go to Craig Federighi (SVP of Software Engineering), who did a fantastic job as the unofficial MC. He brought an energy and charisma that was not only commanding, but also sincere.
It felt like Apple was the underdog again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Porch, Our Street</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-11-chimero-twitter.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-09-11-chimero-twitter.html</guid>
      <description>Frank Chimero:
 Here’s the frustration: if you’ve been on Twitter a while, it’s changed out from under you. Christopher Alexander made a great diagram, a spectrum of privacy: street to sidewalk to porch to living room to bedroom. I think for many of us Twitter started as the porch—our space, our friends, with the occasional neighborhood passer-by. As the service grew and we gained followers, we slid across the spectrum of privacy into the street.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yours Truly, Speaking at Mount Union&#39;s Graduation</title>
      <link>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-13-umu-commencement.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dreger.me/_posts_archive/blah/2014-05-13-umu-commencement.html</guid>
      <description>Three days ago, I graduated from the University of Mount Union. As the president of the Class of 2014, I had the distinct pleasure of giving the closing speech for our graduation ceremony, and the response has been overwhelming. To all those who reached out, for all the kind words and wishes, I give a heartfelt &amp;ldquo;thank you,&amp;rdquo; and I feel incredibly blessed to have such good friends and family.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>